good afternoon until you have a holiday today
добрый день до у вас сегодня праздник
congratulates you independence us
поздравляет независимости вас нас
today is not independence day
сегодня не день независимости там
called diversion you give what is this
называется диверсию вы дадите что это за
holiday why not June 12
праздник почему не 12 июня
just russia day in less look here
просто день россии в менее смотрите вот
he we go to wikipedia see what it is
он мы заходим википедии смотрим что это
for the day of Russia until 2002 it was called
за день россии он до 2002 года назывался
day of the proclamation of the state
день провозглашения там государственного
sovereignty just in the ninetieth year you
суверенитета просто в девяностом году вы
collapse the Soviet Union you proclaimed
развалит советский союз вы провозгласили
its independence from
свою независимость от
you are 32 years old as an independent state
вас 32 года как независимое государство
the birth of addiction turns honey and
рождение зависимости получается мед и
lots of examples it's called the agenda
масса примеров это его называют agenda
strong day consider let's ignite
сильный день рассмотрите давайте зажжем
quieter flair here I go day of russia
чутье потише вот я захожу день россии
June 12, 1990 at the first congress
12 июня 90 года на первом съезде
People's Deputies of the USSR, the measure was adopted
народных депутатов ссср мера принята
declaration in their state
декларация в государством своих
interests with a part of that day and did
интересов с а часть этого дня и сделали
holiday
праздник
yes, why is it on the 12th
да ну а почему он именно 12-го числа про
hare you wanted to ask something well
заяц вы что-то хотели спросить ну
specifically, I want to understand what is the essence
конкретно я хочу разобраться в чем суть
this holiday
этого праздника
just a holiday day of russia well i go
просто праздник день россии ну я езжу
let's just really hope but why
допустим просто правда надеюсь но почему
this matters here we don't have a day
не это matters вот у нас нет день
Ukraine we have addiction day and
украины у нас есть день зависимостью и
but because you got a state
но потому что вы обрели государственный
judgment on the day when we have centuries
суд в тот день когда века у нас
statehood it happens before
государственность она бывает до этого
call names independence day
обзываться день независимости
wrong, that's exactly what you were looking at
неправильно вот вот именно что смотрели
12 and me 90 you proclaimed
12 и меня 90 года вы провозгласили
sovereignty
суверенитет своей
but once again I tell us statehood
но еще раз говорю нас государственности
she long enough starting address
она достаточно долго начиная адрес
soviet union wait no interruption
советский союз подождите не перебивать
it's waiting for fat up
это ждет жира до
through respectively the Soviet Union
через соответственно советский союз
Russian empire and what is yours
российская империя а какое ваше
the state is related to the Russian
государство имеет отношения к российской
empire
империи
direct most no you are watching russia
прямом самое нет вы смотрите россия
she acknowledged as the successor
призналась она правопреемником
soviet you can think so we i
советского вы можете так считать мы я
I just want to understand
хочу просто разобраться смотрите
The Soviet Union did not recognize itself under
советский союз не признавал себя при
the successor of the Russian empire, yes then
правопреемником российской империи да то
have you eat when you are the right successor
есть вы есть когда вы праве преемник
the Soviet Union are considered below you
советского союза считаетесь ниже вас
talking about you didn't hear the most important thing
говорим о вы не услышали самое главную
phrase legal yes and how else
фразу юридические да а как еще
speaking of historical
если говорить именно об исторической
succession yes we believe that
преемственности да мы считаем что
historical and successors as a Soviet
историческим и преемники как советского
union such russia from 3 in what
союза такой россия из 3 в каком
this document is fixed let's say more
документе это зафиксировано скажем еще
since I say I didn’t say legal
раз говорю я же не сказал юридического
lazy presence tic who
ленитесь наличие тически кто
fixed that the exit of the letter is right here
зафиксировала что выезде литеры прям вот
trying to interrupt me and something
пытаетесь меня перебить и на что-то
clarify
уточнить
was normal Russian I said
был нормальным русским языком я сказал
historically we consider ourselves historically
исторически мы считаем себя исторически
we are who the Soviet Union people living
мы это кто советского союза люди живущие
in Russia people live in the service of someone
в россии люди живут сервисе кто-то
considers himself there
считает себя там
assignee there historical gold
правопреемником там исторический золотой
hordes for example, but it is quite possible if with
орды например но вполне возможно если с
given that the ancients tame some
учетом того что древние ручным некоторое
time was really within the scope
время входило действительно в сферу
Mongolian kingdom or actually was
монгольского царство или фактически была
part yes maybe not if we look
частью да возможно не если мы посмотрим
on the territory of Russia and the peoples
на территории россии так и народы
inhabiting that majority and territory
населяющие то большинство и территории
peoples, they were part of the golden
народов они входили в состав золотой
hordes turns out
орды получается
golden horde after mammologist how it is
золотая орда после маммолог как это
called the Mongol-Tatar yoke
называется монголо-татарского ига
in fact, she is at least Russia
фактически русь она по крайней мере
most of it was included in
большую часть ее включили в состав
the golden horde we paid not to give it
золотой орды мы платили не дать ему
actually paid taxes in denmark taxes
платили по сути налоги в дании налоги
forest it was it was on the bow it was than
лес это было это было на лук это был чем
different tax and tribute then see
отличается налог и дань тогда смотрите
it was not a tribute it was an exit tax
это был не дань это был выход налог
territory tax it was called exit
налог с территорию это называлось выход
that is, this is a tribute and than a tribute from a tax
то есть это дань а чем дань от налога
then different just i don't wait
тогда отличается просто я не подождите
I'll tell you more it was a blog we entered
еще расскажу это был блог мы входили в
the composition of the golden horde we have grand dukes
состав золотой орды у нас великие князья
went to the barn until a certain time
ездили в сарай до определенного времени
Ira received labels for reigning, yes then
получали иру ярлыки на княжение да то
there is basically
есть это в принципе
full composition all the signs that we
полный состав все признаки того что мы
moreover, they entered our churches
входили более того в церквях у нас
Orthodoxy when Orthodox
православия когда православные
priests, they also offered prayers for
священники они же молитвы возносились за
three emperors we will conditionally call them
трех императоров условно назовем их
emperors for three kings for the Latin
императорами за трех царей за латинского
well, that is, it is accordingly sacred
ну то есть это соответственно священная
the Roman Empire for the Chinese and for
римская империя за китайского и за
Mongolian arch something that I don’t know for the first time
монгольского арки то что не знаю впервые
I also hear until recently
слышу я тоже до недавнего момента не
knew enough for me too
знал для меня тоже было достаточно
amazing yes it was like that for me
удивительному да это было такое для меня
this also turned out to be extremely surprising from 9
это тоже оказалось крайне удивить от 9
you hear yourself years already and I'm there course
слышишь лет уже себя причем я там курс
I read lectures, I don't remember now
лекций читал я сейчас не вспомню
it was almost a year ago just books
это было почти год назад просто книжек
a lot just watch you soil regret with
много просто смотрите вы почва жалею с
help you for some reason in russia in the composition
помощью вы почему-то в россии в состав
Russia includes a lot of people with
россии входит очень много народа это с
no states he 199 look here i am
не государства он 199 смотрите вот я
opened the Russian constitution so there is not
открывал конституцию россии так там не
say that this is the state of Russians
скажешь что это государство русских
so something to the quarrels leg of the national
так-то к ссорам нога национального
the people of our verbal that is why you
народа нашего verbal то есть почему вы
then
тогда
discard the history of other nations and
откидываете историю других народов так и
take only taliv
берете только талив
for example, the Tatars were from the same story and
например татар были от одну историю и
why how how they relationship or
почему как как они отношениями или
some one is always stronger
какой-то там он всегда сильнее
moreover, the Mongol Empire
монгольской империи больше причем
look, I didn’t say about Russia, I said
смотреть я же не сказал о руси я сказал
we consider ourselves the successors of the Soviet
мы считаем себя преемниками советского
union and the Russian empire at least
союза и российской империи как минимум
but then give through the centuries we believe that
но потом дать через века мы считаем что
he is the source of our statehood
источник нашего государственности он в
ancient Russia, yes, that's right, you're interesting
древней руси да все верно ты интересного
that is, it turns out that the Chechens
то есть получается что у чеченцев
Buryats Bashkirs Tatars source
бурятов башкиров татары источник
statehood in Kievan Rus and
государственности в киевской руси и
why did they join the Russian
почему они присоединились к российской
empires in their time in one way or another
империи в свое время тем или иным
look at the way, I suppose there were couples
способом на смотри я пары допустим были
attached partly voluntarily
присоединены частично добровольно
partly really violently during
частично действительно насильно во время
campaigns of the same Ivan the Terrible, let's say
походов того же ивана грозного допустим
on the Volga of questions not in Kazan Kazan
на волгу вопросов не в казань казань
although they took Ivan with this army
брали хотя при этом войске ивана
there was a sufficient amount of formidable then
грозного было достаточное количество то
so that is it was well as if someone was
так то есть это был ну как бы кто-то был
for someone was against everything as usual
за кто-то был против все как обычно это
it turns out then the Chechens are there and you
получается то тогда чеченцы там а ты
Bashkirs are now occupied
башкиры это сейчас оккупированные
territories bought by the common people
территории купированные народа общего у
so decided someone dreamed voluntarily
так решили кто-то приснился добровольно
someone doesn't but like someone don't go with
кто то нет но как кто-то не идут с
occupied raise but when then
оккупированные повысить но когда то
perhaps it could be called
наверное это можно было назвать как
was occupied there
оккупирован там была своя
statehood yes quite already everything is here
государственность да вполне уже все сюда
there was a state and this Danila is far from
было государства и этот данилы далеко не
everywhere but see what you can
везде но смотрите какую можно
statehood let's say well
государственность допустим говорить ну
we can talk about statehood
можно говорить о государственности
Siberian Khanate but what
сибирского ханства но какой
statehood is possible
государственности допустим можно
let's say so among the people
говорить ну скажем так у народности
Germans or Khanty
немцев или хантов
there was no statehood
государственности как таковой не было
so how there as such and
поэтому как там как такового и
there was no resistance because there was no
сопротивления не было потому что не было
it is proven that you resist because
доказано что сопротивление вы потому что
their very few Nero was
их очень малочисленное нерон был
expelled, let's say for those who were
отчислен вот то допустим у тех кто были
at least some rudiments of statehood
хоть какие-то зачатки государственности
organizations, let's say the Chukchi for some
организации допустим у чукчи на какую-то
why read more Chukchi fought a friend
зачем читать больше чукчу другом воевали
really
действительно
it's nothing less it's outfits subdued or
это нет меньше это наряды покорён или
otherwise I am not from you, I immediately said yes
иного я от вас не я сразу сказал да
someone joined far away
кто-то присоединился далеко не
voluntarily historical continuity
добровольно историческую преемственность
Russian Empire let's still want
российской империи давайте еще хочу
it is interesting to discuss ours with you
подискутировать нашего с вами интересно
it's okay for us to talk
нам это нормально разговаривать
if you look here was the emperor
если смотреть вот был император
nikolay the second last on was
николай второй последний на был
last yes yes you had february on
последним да да у вас был февраль на
february 17 maidan
февраля 17 года майдан
the king's finale was not quite an analogy here
финале царя было не совсем тут аналогия
not directly to him local there was a revolution
не прямо ему местная там была революция
maidan is dory taken and I will give you
майдан есть дори взятым а я дам у вас
it's a coup revolution to them joy and
это переворота революция к ним радость и
february it was not a maidan coup it was
февраля это был не майдан переворот это
there was a revolution revolution ate a lot well
была революция революции много ел хорошо
but you just understand that the revolution
а в просто вы же понимаете что революции
this is a change of state
это смена государственного строя не
replacement of some citizens
замена одних граждан
it was the monarchy that thwarts trump
именно срывает трамп был монархия
changed to
заменили на
Republic Yes, well, let's take it then
республика да хорошо возьмем тогда
october maidan so lenin already
октябрьский майдан так ленин уже
it turns out he was already on top it was not
получается он уже сверху это был не
maidan is again combat without and therefore
майдан это опять же боевое без а потому
what is here, respectively, what we have
что здесь соответственно то что у нас
the republic has become a different system
республика это стал другой строй
socialism the socialist way
социализм социалистический способ
the form of government has shifted all the time
правления в все время сдвигалась форма
is it turns out that
есть получается что
I agree with you that at that time in
я соглашусь с вами что в тот период в
that period in separate documents
тот период в отдельных документах
indeed at home events could
действительно дома события могли
call a coup but in fact if
называть переворотом но по факту если
look at the definition of revolution is what
смотреть на определению революция то что
it is a social change
это изменение общественного строя
social order, he really
общественного уклада он действительно
the provisional government was changing
менялся было временное правительство
it was a republic it was replaced then
было республика она была заменена то
let's say it happened to you at the age of 17
есть скажем так у вас 17 году произошел
not two maidan doors currency on your
не два майдана двери валюте на по вашей
ladies what is my data came out these
дамская что это мои данными вышли эти
people they don't please and look here
люди они не пожалуйста и смотрите вот
after that there was a part that
после этого была часть которая
associated with the Russian Empire then
ассоциировалось с российской империи то
there are White Guards so it was part
есть белогвардейцы так было часть
which created a new state and
которая создала новое государство и
soviet soviet russia then she
советск советская россия то она
exterminated people who historically
истребляла людей которые исторически
associated themselves with
ассоциировали себя с
The Russian Empire was in a civil war
российской империи шла гражданская война
yes, look at the prices of the Soviet Union, he
да ну смотрите на цены советский союз он
historically unrelated to
исторически не имел отношение к
Russian Empire though he tore off
российской империи правда он оторвал
historical Russian empire
исторический российской империи
politically to historically but some
политически до исторически но какие-то
separate radical elements of course
отдельные радикальные элементы конечно
Well, how does it work again, come on, let's
ну как еще раз получается давай давайте
I'll explain to you a little when let's
я немножко вам поясню когда давайте было
a little more, look at any time
чуть больше ну смотрите в любой момент
during any revolution absolutely
при проведении любой революции абсолютно
any first thing the new government does is
любой первое что делает новая власть это
rejects all previous
отторгает все прежние
it says the old world is utterly destroyed
говорится старый мир дотла разрушен
we will build a new one like this
новый мы построим примерно так так было
during the French Revolution
во время великой французской революции
so it will probably be with any revolution
так наверное будет при любой революцию
here is completely changing completely
вот абсолютно меняется полностью весь
way then happens just want
уклад потом происходит просто хочу
back, that is, this is the pendulum
обратно то есть вот это вот маятник он
shifts to a more balanced state
сдвигается в более равновесное состояние
such orders begin to appear during
начинают водиться такие ордена во время
correspondingly later than
соответственно более позднее чем
revolution, that is, it is 20-30 years old
революция то есть она 20-30 лет такие
orders like Nakhimov are so extraordinary
ордена как нахимова такие неординарные
Kutuzov, that is, begins
кутузова то есть начинается
fence let's say some historical
забор скажем так неких исторических
elements
элементов
which were previously denied, for example, the same
которые ранее отрицались например та же
phrase of comrades and raw materials about Stalin
фраза товарищей и сырье насчет сталина
about the baptism of Russia when
по поводу крещения руси когда
someone I don't remember which director
кто то я уже не помню кто из режиссеров
presented him with a version of the film that
представила ему версию фильма о том что
the baptism of Russia is all what obscurantism
крещение руси это все какому мракобесие
church is bad and he said next
церковь это плохо и он сказал следующую
the phrase that at that time it was
фразу что на тот момент это было
progressively it was right i.e.
прогрессивно это было правильным то есть
people focusing on the knowledge that
люди ориентируясь на те знания которые
had at the time they acted absolutely
имели в то время они поступали абсолютно
in the right way, that is, he is no longer
правильным образом то есть он уже не
denied did not reject not in general
отрицала не отвергал не в общем-то
well, the story that was before him, therefore
ну историю которая была до него поэтому
here you can say yes
здесь можно говорить да какие то
radicals may be present remember
радикалы могут присутствовать вспомните
he's really good
хороший такой он хороший действительно
the movie was semi called state
фильм полу назывался государственная
the border is, well, look at least 1
граница это вот ну посмотрите хотя бы 1
firms are quite interesting to us, especially
фирмам достаточно интересны нам особенно
the first film is a border officer
первый фильм это офицер пограничной
the guards are precisely the officer of the royal border
стражи именно офицер царской пограничной
guards and that's how it goes
стражи и вот как у него происходит
becoming it in translation from
становление его в перевод от
own revolutionary events and how
собственного революционных событий и как
he then goes to the service in general to
он потом выходит на службу в общем-то к
red here again, do not forget
красным тут опять же не нужно забывать
that the Reds have conditional advice yes, well, if
что у красных условно советов да ну если
divide the entire officer corps, well, how
весь офицерский корпус поделить ну как
at least 30 percent of the officer corps
минимум 30 процентов офицерского корпуса
gone to them
ушло к ним
that is, it then gave birth to some
то есть это потом рождала какие-то
subsequent friction problems but in
последующие проблемы трения но в
principle
принципе
the fact that they completely cut off contact with
то что они разрывали полностью связь с
past but it was more declarative
прошлым но это больше было декларативно
in my mind she's just here let's say ya
на мой взгляд она просто вот скажем я
still can't catch the moment like you
все-таки не могу поймать момент как вы
historical related
исторические связанные с
Russian coat of arms because beat that you
российский герб потому что избил что вы
historical and political and legal
исторический и политический и юридически
associated with the Soviet Union you announced
связаны с советским союзом вы огласили
that you are the assignee where but
что вы есть правопреемника гда но
the Soviet Union was neither historical
советский союз он не был ни историческим
don't shoot through the toric was
не палите через торические был
legally harmless he denied
юридически не навреди чески он отрицал
continuity but historical was in
преемственность но исторический был в
than asks than the wedding of ra absolutely
чем просит чем свадьбу ра абсолютно
culture continuity of culture
культура преемственность культуры
the Soviet Union did not deny Pushkin and
советский союз не отрицал не пушкина и
Dostoevsky not Tolstoy studied all this
достоевского не толстого изучали все это
well let's talk about asked that is
ну давайте поговорим о спросили то есть
culture born and let's say so
культуру рожденную и скажем так
produced in the Russian Empire
произведенную в российской империи
soviet union in full what is called
советский союз полностью что называется
took in
принял в себя
but we all studied Pushkin Onegin, yes we
но мы все изучали пушкина онегина да мы
everyone studied mushroom eaters grief from mind
все изучали грибоедов горе от ума
as they say, there is nothing to worry about
как говорится тут ничего страшного нет
at the same time, both Griboedov and Pushkin are completely
при этом и грибоедов и пушкин вполне
you can call yourself tsarist officials like that
себе царские чиновники можно так назвать
one diplomat 2 don't remember collegiate
один дипломат 2 уже не помню коллежский
assessor or something, well, although not with this
асессор что ли ну хотя нет этим
chamber junker in my opinion unfortunately how
камер-юнкером по моему к сожалению как
I don't really remember the details so
бы я подробности особо не помню поэтому
culture she was in demand that is
культура она была востребована то есть
she was completely accepted by the fact that some
ее полностью приняли то что какие-то
moments were indeed denied and even
моменты действительно отрицались и даже
historical films especially
исторические фильмы особенно
eighties look they are very
восьмидесятых посмотрите они очень
interesting by the way, also a series filmed
интересные кстати тоже серия снятая
together with the GDR this is a series about youth
совместно с гдр это серия про юность
Petra, that is
петра то есть
russia young laptop and others quite well
россия молодая ноут и прочим вполне себе
this continuity can be shown there
там могут показана эта преемственность
she was serious at first
она была то что на первых порах серьезно
denied yes this is normal
отрицали ну да это нормальное явление
for any revolutionary events
для любых революционных событий есть
turns out at first you didn't and didn't have
получается сначала вы не и не имели
nothing to do with the Russian Empire
никакого отношения к российской империи
and then it was necessary to say the construct
а потом надо было говорить конструкт
entrusted exit always burned look
доверили выход всегда горел смотрите
take this as an example, look again
возьмём вот например еще раз смотрите
job if i say now
работу если я сейчас скажу что ну
allowable
допустим
that I'm not sitting on a chair, but on a rocket, well
что я сижу не на стуле а на ракете ну
how can i declare anything
как бы я могу декларировать что угодно
and ice but at the same time this is this one
так и льда но при этом это вот вот эта
design will always remain
конструкция навсегда всегда останется
a chair in the office roughly speaking there I am not
стул в офисном грубо говоря там я не
I know what kind of computer they call it
знаю каким компьютерном как его называют
so that I do not declare there is some
чтобы я не декларировал есть какая-то
objective reality in objective
объективная реальность в объективной
reality, the Soviet Union has always been
реальности советский союз всегда был
bound culturally always taught
связан культурно всегда преподавались
universities Russian culture Russian
вузов российская культура российская
anal history taught under different
история анала преподаваться под разными
corners but if dear has always been to me
углами но если дорогим всегда была мне
it seems that just in the Soviet
кажется что вот как раз в советском
union and here it is the same Russian language
союзе и вот он тот же самый русский язык
used simply as a lingua franca
использовалась просто как лингва франка
that is, the language for intercultural everything is so
то есть язык для межкультурного все так
as in modern Russia you look in
как и в современной россии вы смотрите в
Russian constitution enshrined in you
конституцию вас закреплен российский
language as a language of international communication
язык как язык межнационального общения
Russian language is still in Russian
русский язык он таки на русский язык
language between national communication
язык между национальным общение
multinational people of the Russian
многонационального народа российской
federation, that is, it's like a lingua
федерации то есть это вот как лингва
such a franc so she wouldn't leave like that
франка такой так она бы не уходит как то
due to the fact that it is Russian there
из за того что это там российской
empire or then there is no such thing anywhere
империи или тогда нет нигде такого
I I look I understand for myself here
я я смотрите я для себя разбираюсь вот
this is this I don't want to convince you not to
это this я не хочу вас переубедить от не
I want to be loved
хочу чтобы меня полюбили
and then look, you remember
а еще тогда вот смотрите вы вспомнили
about Russia, then I can’t tell me no one
про русь вот я тогда не могу мне никто
from Russians cannot explain when
из россиян не может пояснить а когда
let's say if that's even represents that
скажем если вот даже представляет что
Moscow was part of this Kievan Rus so
москва входил этом в киевскую русь так
conditionally to when from what moment
условно по когда с какого момента
the capital became not Kyiv-Moscow
столица стала не киев-москва
but let's look at the Kyiv pen
но смотрите киевская ручку таки давайте
let's define this is not a state
определимся это не государство это
historical period for all Russians
исторический период за все русские
divers well, because it's just a fact
дайверы ну потому что это факт просто
one of the problems if you want to think clearly
одна из проблем если хочешь ясно мыслить
criteria should be clearly defined and
нужно ясно определять критерии и давать
to a certain theses and ok today then
к определенной тезисы и ок сегодня то
there was an ancient Russian state
есть было древнерусское государство
which had several capitals
которого было несколько столиц первая
the capital was Ladoga the second capital was
столица была ладога вторая столица была
in novgorod the third capital was in Kyiv
в новгороде третья столица была в киеве
respectively, then it was Vladimir and
соответственно потом это был владимир и
then, respectively, the capital from
потом соответственно столице из
Vladimir moved to Moscow, although she could
владимира перешла в москву хотя могла
go to Tver and at what point is the capital
перейти в тверь а в какой момент столица
from Kyiv and who moved the capital from Kyiv
из киева и кто перенес столицу из киева
in Vladimir, for example, let me to
во владимир например пусть и я к
unfortunately I didn't remember
сожалению не вспомнил у
for some reason I'm spinning this knuckle
меня почему-то крутится этого крупку
Dolgorukova but I'm not sure honestly
долгорукова но я не уверен честно
because it just turns out
потому что просто получается как бы
tyaf-tyaf-tyaf was then such a hole and then
тяф-тяф-тяф был потом дыра такая а потом
moscow there is no hole there the thing is
москва нет там ни дыра там дело в том
why was it postponed, I remember exactly the case
что почему перенесли я точно помню дело
in that, since I was in Kyiv
в том что так как в киеве был
grand princely throne then all the princes
великокняжеский престол то все князья
the surrounding people constantly went to Kyiv and
окрестные постоянно ходили на киев и
arranged strife precisely for the kiwi
устраивали усобицы именно самому киви
kiwi just fell into disrepair in again i
киви просто пришел в упадок в опять же я
heard one of the interesting theories on my
слышал одну из интересных теорий на мой
look quite an interesting theory that
взгляд вполне интересная теория том что
the decline of the general so-called Kievan
упадку общее так называемой киевской
Russia and but the Old Russian state
руси и но древнерусского государства
led the crusades
привели крестовые походы
very interesting theory
очень интересная теория могу в принципе
to tell that is, let's talk about what
рассказать то есть давайте так про какой
century we say that we are companies
столетии мы говорим что компании мы
now talking about the decline began at 12
сейчас говорим о упадок начался в 12
century in general, that is, the reason
веке общем-то то есть и причину
is called the following which is previously the path of
называется следующее что ранее путь из
the Varangian provided the Greeks, let's just say
варяг в греки обеспечивал ну скажем так
certain collection of taxes which
определенная сбор налогов которые
helped keep the state united
помогали держать единое государство был
a certain excess since trading
определенный избыток так как торговый
the path was well maintained when
путь неплохо эксплуатировался когда же
roughly speaking, Europe managed for itself
грубо говоря европа сумела под себя
pick up the whole coast that is him
подобрать все побережье то есть ему
became safe for let's say swimming
стало безопасным для скажем так плава
crossing which sea come on
пересечения какого моря давай
mediterranean, that is, my way from the Varangians to
средиземного то есть мой путь из варяг в
the river, it’s not quite January, just yes, and
реке он же не совсем января просто да и
just a switchman version of syria over there
просто стрелочник версия сирия вот туда
that is, the goods are already with you in the end
вот то есть товар уже с вами в итоге
street aspired to the one that is
street стремились в ту что то есть
Constantinople but create a region either
константинополь но творят регион то ни
was the end point there goods
было конечной точкой там товар
trade went on accordingly
товарооборот шел дальше соответственно
when from Europe it was possible more
когда из европы можно было более
it is safe now to carry everything somewhere
безопасно теперь возить все куда-нибудь
to Central Asia, let's call it not average
в среднюю азию назовем это не средняя
wrong to the middle east it was possible
неправильно на ближний восток можно было
it is already safe to transport the goods
возить товар уже безопасно посадить ему
the sea is corny more profitable because
моря это банально выгоднее потому что
through the sky through the rapids to carry expensive
через небо через пороги таскать дорого
uncomfortable and hard, respectively
неудобно и тяжело то соответственно
cash flow began to expire and and
поток денежный начал истекать и и
the state began to collapse
государство начало просто разрушаться
just in this period
как раз вот в этот период
fragmentation when Kievan Rus
раздробленности когда киевская русь
yes, I just didn’t understand then, but from the Varangians
это да просто не понял тогда а из варяг
thin and then to Constantinople
худой и тогда в константинополь вот по
this alternative theory began
этой альтернативной теории начали
deliver
доставлять
to the Mediterranean Sea, too, this is necessary
до средиземного моря тоже к это надо
was to be delivered by trucks
было доставить фурами груза
the question is somehow more specific candy you
вопрос как-то поконкретней конфете вы
such a historical hypothesis was said
такую историческую гипотез сказали
interesting that I heard such a hepato I
интересную что я слышал такую гепато я
I just want to understand also for myself and
просто хочу понять еще тоже для себя и
understand that first along the Dnieper so
понять что сначала по днепру так
essentially fused from the Varangians to
сплавляли по сути из варяг в
constantinople
константинополь
goods and now because of the fact that there
товары а теперь из за того что там
someone took control of everything
кто-то взял под контроль все
the Mediterranean began in a different way, but
средиземноморье начали другим путем но
another way in the mediterranean village
другим путем в селе средиземном море
also somehow it was necessary to open the door to deliver
тоже как-то надо было отворят доставить
it's all somehow up delivered through
это все как-то до доставляли через
Europe by land and over mainly
европу сухим путем и поводу в основном
not by dry route but by rivers
не сухим путем а по рекам
what
что
most of the well naturally rivers they
большая часть ну естественно реки они
either in by they usually flow into Europe
либо в по они впадают как правило европе
to the seas either north or there to the south
в моря либо север либо туда на юг
accordingly, it is easier to float down the river
соответственно сплавлять проще по реке
the point is that the way is it enough
дело в том что путь же он достаточно
the long one was really rapid
длинный было действительно порожистой
then there was no ges which
тогда же не было ни гэс который
would accordingly raise the level where
соответственно подняли бы уровень где
could swim safely
можно было бы спокойно проплывать
how many of these portages were there when
сколько там было вот этих волоков когда
just ships these health to style
просто корабли вот эти здоровье до стиля
dragged it just hard in europe
перетаскивали это просто тяжело в европе
this was not the channel the barge drove the donkey
такого не было канал баржа ослик погнали
what is called dragged punts
что называется дотащили плоскодонки
reloaded as soon as
перегрузили повезли как только
the mediterranean sea became whole
средиземное море стало целостно
control this most important ones
контролироваться этот самое главное те
ports of syria modern israel were
порты сирия современные израиле были
taken under control but I'm like that again
взяты под контроль но я такую опять же
We don't like this theory
эта теория нам не нравится моя не
did not dive deep
глубокую не погружался
respectively as soon as control
соответственно как только вот контроль
a stream appeared after not a while began
появился поток через не пор началось
hiccup, that is, they just began to use
икать то есть просто стали пользоваться
alternative machine subject
альтернативной машины предмете
returns to less and incomes less and
доходности до меньше и доходы меньше и
well, some excess money and no
ну избыточные какие-то деньги и нет
excess money no no possibility
избыточных денег нет нет возможности
to keep a single state she began
держать единое государство она начала
crumble so that everyone somehow with
рассыпаться чтобы ему каждый как-то со
I was there with my piggy bank and then we'll be back
своей копилкой там был а потом вернёмся
to our question in Kyiv, respectively
к нашему вопросу в киеве соответственно
there was a grand throne all there
был великокняжеский престол все туда
walked around Kyiv trampled Kyiv ruined
ходили по киеву топтались киев разорялся
regularly but when one army comes
регулярно но когда приходит одна армия
knocks out another army then the next one
вышибает другую армию потом следующая
the army is next in the end the city is just
армия следующая в итоге город просто
sooner or later it will fade, well, purely
рано или поздно захиреет ну чисто
because you are ruined by war
потому что вы разоряют войной
matching at some point from Kyiv
соответствие в какой-то момент из киева
the capital was simply transferred to Vladimir
столицу просто перенесли во владимир
because already Kyiv as such
потому что уже киев как такового а
why then these all the princes do not
почему тогда этим всем князьям не
Vladimir himself wanted to go and
хотелось так же самого владимир ходить и
bust it listen well for that moment
разорять его слушайте ну на тот момент
as far as I remember closer there already
насколько я помню ближе там уже
almost failed because
практически не успели потому что
the Mongol-Tatar invasion began then
началось монголо-татарское нашествие то
there is a capital in vladimir
есть столица во владимире помол
existed for about 150 years
просуществовала что-то около 150 лет не
she has a very big shoot pro what
у нее очень большой стрелять про какой
period we see what century listen
период мы видим какой столетие слушайте
I can't tell you exactly the dates.
я точно вам по датам не смогу сказать
let's better look then better at
давайте лучше посмотрите то лучше в
internet i or professional not
интернете я или профессиональных не
I'm just not professional myself
просто я тоже не профессиональные сам
programmer on the first call on the second
программист по первым звони по второму
the sheet just turns out in the thirteenth
лист просто получается в тринадцатом
century
веке
which we took ki
котором мы взяли ки
walked there and not let's say the skating rink
там прошлись а не скажем так катком по
many cities yes yes that is and in that
многим города да да то есть и в том
number of faces and peacefully rezaev vladimir i don't
числе лица и мирно резаева владимир я не
I can catch this historical moment
могу поймать вот это исторический момент
when will the transfer
когда получится перенос
vladimir 100 to the capital
владимир 100 до столицы
if i'm not mistaken it was the end
если я не ошибаюсь это был или конец
12th century or 13 listen well yes
12-го века или 13 слушайте ну да
look start just get u
посмотри стартовым просто получается у
we were
нас было
that's rus so she would shilov union that's it
вот русь так она бы шилов союз вот это
lithuanian principality scoreboard lithuanian
литовское княжество табло литовской
russian bench press indian
русский жим индийской
no, I can't say Galician-Volynian
нет я не могу сказать галицко-волынское
Principality of Gallic Linsky is
княжество галльского линская это
a little bit different
чуть-чуть другое
our self account union u what do you have
наш сама счет союзом у а что вы имеете
mind union were you lithuanian
виду союз был ли ты литовское
the state, that is, it turns out not a single
государство то есть получается ни одного
no rus just like rus in the composition
нет русь именно как руси в состав
the state of Lithuania was definitely not included
литовского государства точно не входил
how it didn’t enter but didn’t enter looked
как не входило но не входил смотрели
count and now i
считать и сейчас я
here is the great principality
вот великое княжество
Grand Duchy of Lithuania so here I am
великое княжество литовское так вот я
even opened the Russian Wikipedia because
даже русскую википедию открыл потому что
we have Ukrainian pens for them
у нас за них ручки украински могут
differ grand duchy of lithuania
отличаться великое княжество литовское
Russian and Maltese
русской и же мальтийское
they could declare anything
декларировать они могли то что угодно не
so look and the territories of Kyiv to him what
так смотреть и территории киев ему какие
evidence and modern belarus or is it
улики и современная беларусь или да это
there was one state, let's see
было одно государство смотрите давайте
see which principalities are included
посмотрим какие княжества вошли в состав
I'm just people look at something I see how
я просто люди что-то смотри я вижу как
after that, see which principalities
вот после этого смотрите какие княжества
I am sending the composition of the state and I will not
шлю состав государства и я не буду
now say which specific of those
сейчас сказать какие конкретные из тех
not alone and at least Kyiv but
не одинок и по крайней мере киева но
as far as I remember Murom Ryazan
насколько я помню мурома рязанское
the principality was not included in the fee
княжество не взноса за не входило
novgorod lands don't just enter
новгородские земли не входи просто
look it turns out what if we give
смотрите получается что если мы дадим
that Russia is here with the center was in Kyiv
что русь это вот с центром было в киеве
only snatch so with the capital in Kyiv and
только вырвать так со столицей в киеве а
because even the geographic center
потому что даже географический центр
a little bit wrong, let's see
немножко не то есть мы смотрим давайте
on if moscow has a center russia has a center
на если у москвы центр у россии центр
this is moscow we take the capital of the capital and
это москва мы берем столицу столицы и
the center of this political and economic
центр этом политические и экономические
and cultural
и культурные
will not. chernovil we have a cultural
не станет . чорновил у нас культурная
the capital is considered st. petersburg in general
столица считается санкт-петербург вообще
just if you are watching now in russia
просто если смотрите сейчас в россии
also hit the center with a finger, then we
тоже пальцем в центр стукнуть то мы
we’ll get somewhere nickname to the Germans, but closer to and
куда-то ник немцам попадем но ближе к и
wrapped in wires
окутал проводах
Well, it's more like a geographic center.
ну скорее просто географический центр
has no sense to poke n.c. that's
не имеет sense пальцем тыкать н.к. вот и
it turns out that we
получается что мы
so did the new military-political
так сделали новый военно-политический
union
союз
look I'm not ready to discuss
смотрите я не готов обсуждать
military-political alliance if I even here
военно-политический союз если я даже вот
I can't remember now what
я не могу сейчас вспомнить какие
qualities were part of this
качества входили в состав этого
military-political union is the most important
военно-политического союза самое главное
what period of time and
какой период времени и это
military-political alliance or is it
военно-политический союз или это
state state union state
государство государство союз государстве
ain't it like u even peep beyond slavery
не это как и даже заглянуть за рабство
then which principalities and what period
тогда какие княжества и какой период
time, well, because the state
времени ну потому что государство
formed for a short period of time
образованной на короткий период времени
instant collapsed well and such
моментальной развалившийся ну и такую
history
историю
see if a short period of time
посмотреть если короткий период времени
Russian Empire I am only 200 years old
российской империи мне всего 200 лет
lasted for a short period
просуществовала это короткий период
time well look russian empire
времени ну смотрите российская империя
here I will say this to the Russian empire
тут я скажу так российской империи это
just a name really
всего лишь название на самом деле
empire as empire it existed
империя как империя она существовала
much longer and do not just need it
намного дольше и не нужно просто ее
adjusted to normal
привели в соответствие нормальное
name which is common to European
название которое общей европейским
complied with the rules because the king
правилам соответствовало потому что царь
caesar caesar yes it was the emperor by
кесарь цезарь да это был император по
in fact, we called it the king, but there
сути у нас это называлось царю но там
there were emperors and Peter the Great decided
были императора еще и петр первый решил
just put the name in
всего лишь привести название в
accordance therefore essentially kingdom a
соответствии поэтому по сути царство а
this is an empire on the facts boiled pirates he
это империя по фактам вареный пиратов он
renamed himself roughly
переименовал себя грубо говоря
emperor country empire though before
императора страну империю хотя до этого
everything was exactly the same, but for example
все было ровно также а вот например
take the same Moscow principality
возьмем то самое московское княжество
so but for example if it doesn't hurt me
так но например если мне не сшибает
the rules won there cool in the fifteenth
правит завоевала там круто в пятнадцатом
century to the people of the Novgorod Republic
веке лицам новгородскую республику
a haze of non-citizens yes, that is, it turns out
марево неграждан да то есть получается
then this Moscow was not
то этого москва не было
decline in customers is the successor of rus
спад клиентов это правопреемником руси
that's exactly why
это точно почему
and novgorod good time galley
а новгород доброго времени камбузе
look there was a feature in his uniform
смотрите была особенность в его единое
the state she broke up some
государство она распалась какой-то
periods were principalities separate
периоды были княжества отдельные
principalities fought among each other
княжества боролись между друг с другом
for power were they the successors of that
за власть были ли они преемниками той
Russia it was
русь это были
well vase who will prevail and form
хорошо вазе кто возьмет верх и образует
new unified state
новое единое государство единое
a state based on Russia, this is what decided
государство на базе руси вот это и решал
Moscow could not have won by a planned
могла не москва выиграть плановым
pinning down let's see so let's see
придавив давайте давайте так посмотрим
modern Ukraine is historical
современная украина есть историческим
continuations of this Russia
продолжениями вот этой руси
see what you mean by
смотрите что вы имеете ввиду под
modern ukraine is about modern
современной украины вот-вот современное
humble here we are now watching
смирить вот мы сейчас смотрим
the modern state of russia and
современное государство россия и
modern state of ukraine
современное государство украина
they are and are not political
они есть и не есть политические
juristic documents
юридические документы
here, according to you, Ukraine has
вот по вашему украина есть имеет
political attitude to this Russia
политическое отношение к вот этой руси
whether she was a part of this Russia and what to me
ли она была частью этой руси и что мне
not all pro because i have some
не все про потому что мне некоторые
russians times that russia is related
русские раз что россия имеет отношение
course Ukraine is not available with us there but you
курсе украина не имеется у нас там но вы
see ukraine how ukraine exactly how
смотрите украина как украина именно как
state as statehood
государство как государственность вот
if they are on Ukrainian statehood
если ими на украинскую государственность
yes, it's pretty young
да это достаточно молодая
statehood on like ukraine but
государственности на как украина но
which russia like the russian federation
какие россии как и российской федерации
no, I don't agree with you, look
нет здесь я с вами не согласен смотрите
the situation is quite simple.
ситуация достаточно простая
Ukraine was part of a large state
украина была частью большого государства
you can call it whatever you like Russian
его можно назвать как угодно российская
empire soviet union it was part
империя советский союз это была часть
one big state is like
единого большого государства это как
rus ancient russia disintegrated
русь древняя русь распадалась
united and so on, that is, yes
объединялась и так далее то есть да
Let's say Murom Ryazan Principality
допустим мурома рязанское княжество
could be part of Russia there Russian horns
могло быть частью руси там рожки русские
Well, yes, they are there, after all, they are still
они ну да это там бывшие ведь еще
krivichi there and so on as they were called
кривичи там и так далее как их называли
but they became Russian, respectively, at
но они стали русскими соответственно при
bringing it all apart
объединении вот всего этого врозь
respectively were they part yes but
соответственно были ли они частью да но
you're not talking about let's say some
вы говорите не про скажем так какую-то
historical background about
историческую подоплеку именно про
statehood
государственность
there is a single state, I believe that
есть единое государство я считаю что
modern Russia is the successor
современная россия является преемником
historical of this state you can
историческим этого государства вы можете
consider that yes you were a part of it
считать что да вы были частью этого
states, but not for very
государства но как не за весьма и
state as such of ukraine
государства как такового украины
so why is this modern
подавайте так почему вот современная
russia which is legal there
россия которая там юридический
there are about 20 there 30 years thirty
существует около 20 там 30 лет тридцать
than something and a modern wedge 3 you
чем то ли и современного клина 3 ты
some years territorially ukraine has
чем-то лет территориально украина имеет
relation to these lands
отношение к этим землям
the population is the same as lived here so here
население то же что и жила тут так тут
people who are root in Chernihiv
люди которые рутом в черниговской
Kyiv there Zhytomyr region
киевской там житомирской области
the beginnings of this Russian descendants of those people
начатки этот русски потомки тех людей
who lived right there in this Russia
которые жили вот там в этой руси
turns out to look and what we don't have
получается выглядеть и что мы не имеем
this is politically no relationship
отношения вот это политически нет
look politically or let's say so and
смотрите политически или скажем так и
historically from 3 different things and why
исторически из 3 разные вещи а зачем
then yes what is there dalat you are looking at
тогда да в чем там далат вы смотрите
the question is what are you talking about
вопрос в том что вы говорите про
statehood or history, he is not
государственность либо историю он не
whether Ukraine is related to the ancient
имеет ли украина отношение к древнему
Russian state do has
русскому государственному до имеет
Ukraine was once a part
украина когда-то была частью
ancient Russian state then part
древнерусского государства потом частью
modern ukraine modern
современной украины современное
the state of ukraine was part of
государство украина была частью ну
more precisely, part of the territory was part of
точнее частью территории входила в
the composition of the ancient Russian state because
состав древнерусского государства потому
that take most of the territory
что взять большую часть территории
ukraine she never there old russian
украины она никогда там древнерусского
states but still most of Russia
государства но таки большую часть россии
if and then never its absolutely
если и затем никогда не его абсолютно
right, I don't deny
верно я нисколько не отрицаю
respectively a single state
соответственно единое государство
expanded the territory that was there
расширялась территория которая была там
modern Ukraine by this state
современной украины этим государством
joined later at some point
присоединялась потом в какой-то момент
these lands were roughly given away
эти земли грубо говоря были отданы
transferred to Ukraine formed as they
переданы украине сформировалась как они
to the Ukrainian SSR, which later received
к украинской сср которая потом получила
independence
независимость
that is, as such, you understand the community
то есть как такового общину понимаете
here why it is difficult to speak as such
здесь почему сложно говорить как таковой
nationalism, that is, the nation of nationalism
национализм ну то есть нация национализм
this principle arose somewhere in 1919 and then
этот принцип возник где-то в 1919 да то
there is
есть
Odessa you said religion
одесса вы же говорили вероисповедание
allegiance was a single state
подданство все было единое государство
respectively from this single
соответственно от этого единого
the state withdrew part of the territory
государства отошла часть территории
which is now called modern
которая сейчас называется современная
ukraine
украина причем когда я говорю отошла не
between nothing wrong y'all
не между ничего плохого вы все
states once but get their
государства когда-то но получают свою
independence to the same extent if they are well
независимость той же мере если они ну
no matter how the original ones were formed there
как бы изначальные не образовывались там
millennia ago, so, respectively
тысячелетия назад так вот соответственно
formed the modern state
образовалась современно государство
does ukraine have historical roots
украина имеет ли она исторические корни
in the ancient Russian state before has
в древнерусском государстве до имеет
is she the heir
является ли она скажем так наследником
no in my opinion no but why is that
нет на мой взгляд нет но почему вот
why allergic heir not
почему аллергическим наследником не
is political sorry add
является политическим извините добавлю
historical prehistoric clearly
историческим доисторические явно
kinship is traced heredity
прослеживаются родство наследственность
it's political without question
это без вопросов политические
politically, let's say so united as
политически скажем так единая как
the state inherits well for the current
государство наследует ну на текущий
the moment of the russian federation is simple
момент российской федерации просто
see we
смотрите мы
so I see that the Russian Federation
вот я вижу что российской федерации
inherits the USSR there is a hole here you are
наследует ссср есть дырка вот вы
admit that
признаете что
the Soviet court is political
советский суд есть политическим
I consider the heir of the Russian empire
наследником российской империи я считаю
that no because there was no such thing
что нет потому что не было вот этого
political act we have liri and not
политического акта у нас лири а не
admitted that there is some kind of coil for
признавал что есть какая катушка для
me in non-combat yeah if you don't read
меня в небоевые да если вы не читаете
students, I shield that there is a hole between
студентки я щитаю что есть дырка между
but then dig who I still don’t
но дальше вот копать кого я все-таки не
I see how the transition is like this is Russia
вижу как переход как вот это русь
which was in Kyiv, let's say we won't
которая была в киеве допустим не будем
call her kievski because you
ее назвать киевски потому что вы
think it's just in the 19th century
считаете что это в 19-м веке просто
coined term temporary
придуманный термин временной
the gap is not just invented
промежуток не то что придумано просто
for convenience, let's introduce
введем для удобства чтобы было вот
it is somehow clear to determine the period when
как-то понятно определять период когда
the capital was in the cinema for example they don’t say
столица была в кино например не говорят
Ladoga Rus and
ладожская русь и
very short period there to study nothing
очень короткий период там изучать ничего
understand that is when Rurik but
поймите то есть когда рюрик но
potentially the founder of Russia's most
потенциально основателем россии наиболее
suitable candidate for modern
подходящая кандидатура на современный
moment it
момент это
controversial character
спорный персонаж так
let's say the simplest and therefore
скажем так наиболее простая и поэтому
I say the most suitable way to start
говорю наиболее подходящим так начинать
let's let's find out the authenticity
давайте давайте так достоверность узнать
was Rurik
был ли рюрик
Rurik frieze lansky was definitely a character
рюрик фриз lansky точно был это персонаж
which in the whole history is some kind
который во всей истории какой то какой
then great was some guys look
то велик был какой-то ребят смотрите
it was definitely Rurik frieze lansky in Europe was
точно был рюрик фриз lansky в европе был
there is a discrepancy in terms of dates
есть определенные там неувязка по датам
yes it disappears for a while
да он на какой-то период пропадает это
very suspiciously consistent with
очень подозрительно совпадает с
the appearance of Rurik in Russia, but I don’t
появлением рюрика на руси вот но я не
I will argue about simply and say that
буду утверждать о просто и говорю что
this is the most suitable for the current
это наиболее подходящий на текущий
moment character who fits under
момент персонаж который подходит под
Rurik
рюрика
so let's assume it's rick
соответственно предположим что это рик
if you don't like we can line no
если вам не нравится мы можем линия не
wrote just the studio is not there again
писали просто студия не есть еще раз
there is some kind of professional historian
есть профессиональным историком какие то
we are talking like two citizens then
есть мы беседуем как два гражданина то
there is and well, who is just interested
есть и ну который просто интересуется
there such things that is operation
там такими вещами то есть операция
it's just that there are people who came and already created
просто там люди кто пришел и уже создал
but people to it is not clear where this people are like
но люди к непонятно где этот люди как
here, well, look from what I remember know
тут ну смотрите из того что я помню знаю
Yurik came to the village in Ladoga then
пришел юрик во сел в ладоге затем
accordingly began to select the surrounding
соответственно начал подбирать окрестные
land, he moved to Novgorod, that is
земли он перебрался в новгород то есть
at first he had a ladogi rate, then
сначала у него была ставка ладоги потом
in Novgorod, that is, but as its capital
в новгороде то есть но как столицы его
lands in fact and then things Oleg already
земель по сути а затем вещи олег уже
Helgi is most likely not Oleg, judging by
хельги скорее всего и не олег судя по
name moved the capital to Kyiv how is it
имени перенес столицу в киев как там
it seemed and sit Oleg in Kyiv and
было кажется и сиди олег в киеве и
knyazhich then there is a complete record there
княжич то там такое там запись полное
but from the story of bygone years he called
зато из повести временных лет и назвал
he is Kyiv, then the mother of Russian cities, well, then
он киев то мать городов русских ну то
there is most likely a tracing-paper from the word
есть скорее всего калька со слова
the metropole will turn out to be the time i think the point is
metropole окажется время я думаю дело в
that
том что
we must also understand that
мы должны понимать что тоже в
a certain moment when there
определенный момент когда там была
Catherine so that is a little
екатерина так то есть немножко
rift valley story about this tale
рифт-валли историю об эту повесть
time years, she still does not
временных лет она все таки не при
Catherine was so I don’t mean
екатерине было так что и не имею ввиду
polished this theory of the appearance of Russia
шлифовали вот эта теория появления руси
and well, Catherine Babu only polished in
и ну екатерина бабу только на шлифовал в
let's say what favor
пользу скажем какой
ultra russian good you look
ультра русское хорошо вы посмотрите
for example, if she wasn’t, by the way, she was German
например если не она кстати немка была
she was not pleased she was very
она была ним не радовал она очень
supported Lomonosov precisely on
поддерживала ломоносова именно по
the reason that its let's say so
причине того что его скажем так
potential adversaries in the academy of sciences
потенциальные противники в академии наук
pushed through the so-called well Swedish
проталкивали так называемые ну шведскую
theory roller then he's on somewhere in between
теорию ролик то он на где-то между
the netherlands yes don't just see if
нидерландами да не просто смотрите если
there even you too your people to come there
там даже вы тоже свои люди к пришел там
elite heirs people capri cream
элитами наследники люди капри сливки
it turns out Kyiv was Kyiv was a city
получается киев был киев был городом
what kind of state did you drive there
какое гнала вы какое государство там
It was
было
from what I know states like
из того что я знаю государства как
there was no such thing there were various tribes
такового не было были различные племена
there was a city someone obviously sat there maybe
был города кто-то там явно сидел может
be he was Khazar there is such a well
быть он был хазарским есть такая ну
look, let's see how the city used to be
смотри давайте так был город значит было
already to this political organization
уже к эта политическая организация
see reliable reliable
смотрите достоверных достоверных
written sources unfortunately
письменных источников к сожалению того
very little period I listened I don't know
периода крайне мало я слушал я не знаю
how much to trust these words one of
насколько доверять этим словам один из
full of historians said that all that we
историков полна сказал что все что мы
we know everything about the Slavs until the middle of the 9th century
знаем о славянах до середины 9 века все
Fits a very small notebook
умещается очень небольшую тетрадочку вот
precisely authentic written
именно достоверные письменными
sources
источниками
so what was before is unknown what
поэтому что было до неизвестно то что
these lands were annexed let's say so
эти земли были присоединены скажем так
northerners, that is, the northerners of Slovenia
северянами ну то есть северяне словения
actually came along with the Vikings and
пришли фактически вместе с варягами и
roughly attached books null
присоединили грубо говоря книги null
formed together with local glades
образовали вместе с местными полянами
Drevlyans there is a single state then
древлянами там единое государство потом
Radimichi Krivichi Vyatichi was added there
туда добавили радимичей кривичей вятичей
formed a wall of conditional Kievan Rus
образовало стену условная киевская русь
yes it was that would be I'm sorry
да такое было что было бы я к сожалению
I don't know, that is, it turns out just know
не знаю то есть получается просто знаете
just like this too
тоже такая только вот
Rurik came there or who is there from him
рюрик пришел там или кто там от него
I am writing about you took that is, Kyiv was a city
пишу об ты взял то есть киев был город
was a driver Kyiv could be a city could
был водитель киев мог быть городом мог
not being a city is unprincipled
не быть городом это непринципиально это
just became the capital of a new
всего лишь стала столицей нового
states
государства
let's once again the type was in those days
давайте еще раз тип был по тем временам
highly developed city is not quite
высоко развитым городом то довольно не
if for but see sources
если за но смотрите источников
reliable how long I live in Kyiv who he is
достоверных сколько живу в киеве кем он
was a fairly small town
был был достаточно небольшим городом по
by European standards was well, not the most
европейским меркам был ну не самым
big a
большим а
when he became
когда он стал
quite large but that's when they moved
довольно большим но вот когда перенесли
the capital began development there very
столицу началось развитие там очень
it is good even to trace the development
хорошо даже прослеживаться по развитию
territories for centuries let's remember
территорий по века давайте вспомним
9 it seems like a century how many cities were
9 кажется век сколько городов было
conditional here in this Russian state I
условное вот этой русском государстве я
that's how I remember something was about
вот насколько помню что-то было около
a dozen of them, most of them she's on
десятка из них большая часть она на
territory of modern Russia and closer
территории современной россии и ближе
climb there. novgorod ladoga let's go
туда лезть . новгород ладога давайте вы
somehow aroused me it seems out of common
как-то вызвали мне кажется из общей
world history there began the development
мировой историю там началось развитие
the fact is that in these centuries throughout Europe
дело в том что в эти века по всей европе
urban development began, but because
начались развитие городов а потому что
defined there conditionally so to speak
определенные там условно так скажем
scientific and technical progress
научно-технический прогресс
reached a certain level and
дошёл до определенного уровня и
communications international economy began
муникации международная экономика начала
rise and
подниматься и
began to equip cities in many places
начали города обустраивать много где
look, I say reliable again
смотрите я еще раз говорю достоверных
the information I have is valid
сведений у меня допустим достоверность
him what you have I do not know reliable
ему что у вас есть я не знаю достоверных
information about the development of Kyiv before coming there
сведений развитие киева до прихода туда
I don’t have Varangians, I just have some
варягов у меня нет просто есть какие-то
semi legends unproven things even too
полу легенды недоказанные вещи даже тоже
against skye yo and everything very carefully
против ская лет и все очень внимательно
read very critically because
читайте очень критически потому что
often the same chroniclers simply
частенько те же летописцы просто при
description of events took some
описании событий брали какие-то
known to them, shall we say, facts from
известные им скажем так факты из
the past is just being driven here we are now
прошлого просто подгоняют вот мы сейчас
talking about the tale of bygone years
говорим про повесть временных лет
looked on the display of temporary years she
выглядели на дисплее временных лет она
written, that is, it also turns out here
написана то есть тут тоже получается
there are moments that
есть моменты что
in certain periods so the story
в определенные периоды так повести
adjusted this chronicle to the current
подгонялись этот летописи под текущую
political conjuncture is not quite me it
политическую конъюнктуру не совсем я это
I meant the following
имел ввиду я имел виду следующее что
as such the science of history at that moment
как таковой науки истории в тот момент
was not on
не было на
respectively, but who is
соответственно допустим но кто такой
probably a saint
святой ней наверное
Ipatiev Monastery did not know
ипатьевском монастыре не знали
there is
есть
this is an ancient Roman historian, he is the only one there
это древнеримский историк он там один
considered to be the father of the founders
считается отцом основателей вроде бы
stories they say again, I didn’t read it, I
истории мол опять же я я его не читал я
just heard that it was
просто слышал о том что был такой
character ionu I did such things
персонаж иону такими вещами занимался я
I'm talking about what
говорю о том что
let's say a person
допустим человек
the chronicler had to describe a certain
летописец должен был описать некая
battle events or some kind of political
события битву или какое-то политические
events but he wrote it much later
события но он писал это сильно позже
let's say in a hundred years in a hundred
допустим через сто лет через сто
fifty in 200 years and accordingly
пятьдесят через 200 лет и соответственно
he didn't really know how it happened
он доподлинно не знал как это происходит
he had big gaps to
у него были большие пробелы чтобы
do the job he just took let's say
выполнить работу он просто брал допустим
a story from the bible and instead of some
сюжет из библии и вместо какого-то
conditional Solomon or whether there are any
условного соломона или ли каких-то там
Jesus Christ, he inserted known to him
иисуса христа он вставлял известных ему
characters and described all this therefore
персонажей и все это описывал поэтому
allowable
допустим
when is this the last some books
когда вот это последний какие-то книжки
I read quite to myself there quite
читал я вполне себе там довольно
convincingly showed that you are looking
убедительно показывали что вот смотрите
Ipatiev Chronicle is such and such
ипатьевская летопись вот такая-то
such and such a story it echoes 1 a
такая-то история она перекликается 1 а
here is King Solomon here is the Bible for you
вот вам царь соломон вот вам библия вот
you next there new old testament and
вам следующий там новый старый завет и
all this is history it's up to this all
все это вот истории она до этого все
was I just drag for beauty but
было я просто перетащить для красоты но
this is about how I regard then
это примерно как я расцениваю тогдашнего
chroniclers even probably like no one else
летописцы даже наверно как никого это
political strategist poly technologists pr-manager
политтехнолог поли технологи pr-менеджер
that is, he needs to create a beautiful
то есть ему нужно создать красивую
history, but he knows that some
историю но он знает что произошли некие
events let's say that came to yurik volume
события допустим то пришел в юрик тома
sat down somewhere or Oleg transferred things there
сел где-то или вещи олег там перенес
the capital must be described somehow
столицу куда-то надо как-то это описать
how descriptively does not know he takes
как описательно не знает он берет
familiar plots from here lying nearby
знакомому сюжеты из вот лежащий рядом
of course or caretakers so that is under
конечно или смотрители так то есть под
the current political situation should
текущую политическую конъюнктуру надо
rewrite a little old history
переписать немножко старенькую историю
so it might as well be
так что вот может быть и такое вполне
but again I speak in front of Catherine before
но я опять же говорю при екатерине до
tried to admit when to deny
пытались допустим когда отрицать
in general, the Parisian theory in general
вообще парижскую теорию вообще полностью
eradicate then yes actively exactly by
искоренить тогда да активно именно по
at Catherine's insistence, she did not want
настоянию екатерина она не хотела
kinship with the Swedes in general, nothing special
родства со шведами вообще никак особенно
given the fact that then there were WWII war
с учетом того что тогда были вов война
literally passed with the Swedes
со шведами прошло буквально совсем
recently and have at home we'll tell you so
недавно и иметь у себя расскажем так
ancestors and states in the form of Swedes
прародители и государства в виде шведов
Well, it was considered extremely shameful, so Barty
ну считалось крайне зазор поэтому барти
Germans drank Russian there
российским пили там немцы
managed yes here I don’t know until the end and and
управляли да тут я не знаю до конца и и
background, as it were, Catherine the second even in
подоплеку как бы екатерины второй яже в
I couldn't get my head in, but accordingly
голову не мог залезть но соответственно
I guess it was like this
я предполагаю что было вот так
accordingly, then Lomonosov came out and
соответственно тогда вышел ломоносов и
yes really enough
да действительно достаточно
opportunistic drew this theory
конъюнктурного нарисовал эту теорию
which I liked about the river ros and
которая понравилась про реку рось и
following questions
следующих вопросов
now, for example, let's go back there in
вот сейчас например еще вернемся туда в
modernity is now in many there
современность вот сейчас во многих там
political circles of Russia among citizens
политических кругах россии среди граждан
so there are such here it is necessary to return the land
так бытуют такие вот надо вернуть земли
Russian empire including there
российской империи в том числе там
Ukraine there Finland
украину там финляндию
the Baltics so on so that's how you
балтии так дальше так вот как вы
do you think it was formed by Gandhi the Baltics
считаете это образовал ганди балтия не
heard these and
слышал таких и
well, look again, brave men
ну смотрите опять же отважен мужчины
opinion like but look let's do it right away
мнение как но смотрите давайте так сразу
there are a lot of different opinions in chatroulette
в чат-рулетке мнению очень много разных
and they do not always reflect I would
и они далеко не всегда отражают я бы
said not far apathetically
сказал недалеко апатично никак не
reflect what people think and say
отражают то что думают и говорят люди ну
in general, as they say statistics
вообще как это говорят статистике
sampling is not
выборка не
respectively
соответственно
about the Baltics, to be honest and
по поводу балтии честно говоря и
Finland from you the first I hear is to me
финляндии от вас первую слышу есть мне
personally, even piled up maybe maybe
лично даже навалено может быть может
I do not argue to be in chatroulette. someone
быть в чат-рулетке не спорю . кого-то
this is my personal opinion but look for not
это мое личное мнение но смотрите для не
hangs out from Ukraine, here Ukraine is easier
болтается с украины вот украина проще
market do you think should russia
market как вы считаете должна россии
return Ukraine as if
вернуть себе украину как будто
historically there are Russian lands
исторически там русские земли земли
Russian Empire well, look, I think
российской империи ну смотрите я считаю
that Russia should provide its
что россия должна обеспечивать свою
strategic security
стратегическую безопасность ну как
Russian citizen I want my
гражданин россии я хочу чтобы мое
state
государство
stood what is called on the ground confidently
стояла что называется на земле уверенно
firmly provided my personal
твердой обеспечивала мою личную
safety
безопасность
respectively, if to ensure this
соответственно если для обеспечения этой
security will need to seize
безопасности нужно будет захватить
Ukraine
украину
to do it there turns you out
на это сделать есть получается вы
imperialists you marry me realist
империалисты вы выходите за меня реалист
well, as I say, if this is necessary
ну как я говорю если для этого нужно
if it can be avoided and Sarmatian
если это можно избежать и сарматских
come on and in a logical way and better these
давай и логическим путём и по лучше эти
let's take it politically
политическим путем давай давайте заберём
now if brackets so here now here
вот если скобки так вот вот сейчас вот
the current situation is already clear here
современные ситуации тут уже ясен
political alignment do you think
расклад политический как вы считаете
should russia now seize ukraine
должна россия сейчас захватить украины
to ensure your safety
чтобы обеспечить свою безопасность
the war has begun no one will understand at all
война началась никто не поймёт вообще не
will accept I'm sure in Russia if it's just
примет я уверен в россии если просто
russia is getting wrong right now
россия становится прямо сейчас не так
conclusion your personal opinion should
вывод свое ваше личное мнение должна
seize ukraine or not
захватить украину или нет для
ensure your safety
обеспечения своей безопасности трите
the war has already begun to ensure
война уже началась для обеспечения
some security is declared
безопасности ну декларируются какие-то
certain intentions
определенные намерения так ведь
declared purpose declared reason
декларируются цели декларируется причине
here you are, as a citizen of Russia, do you think
вот вы как гражданин россии вы считаете
what should russia have captured
что должна россия захватили должна
still stop in this military
все-таки прекратить в этот военную
operation in ukraine but stop for sure
операцию в украине но прекратить точно
no why
нет а почему
well, firstly it will cause an internal
ну во первых это вызовет внутренний
political crisis almost certainly
политический кризис почти однозначно
that is, it is necessary to fight in Ukraine in order to
то есть воевать в украине надо для того
so that there is no rally in Russia and
чтобы не было митинга в россии так и
remembers the question is not simply rallies, but what
помнит вопрос не митингах попросту а что
this will cause an internal political
это вызовет внутренний политический
crisis and potentially negative
кризис и потенциально это негативно
will affect the king's country stuffed well
скажется на стране короля набит хорошо
from there to what tape should fight
оттуда до какого лента должна воевать
russia in ukraine exactly until the moment
россия в украине ровно до момента
capitulation comrades Zelensky company
капитуляции товарищи зеленского компания
that is, you get as a citizen
то есть вы получается как гражданин
Russians now think that you personally
россии сейчас считаете что вот вы лично
never abstract, but what do you personally
никогда не абстрактными а вы лично что
continue the war, well, a special operation like
войну продолжать ну спецоперацию как у
you are told to continue, are you a klimets or
вас говорят продолжать вы климец или
you can call me calmly change
можно называть я спокойно смена
most strict so no special operation
большинство строгой так не спецоперации
ready in bulk and let's just say
готовый на навалом а скажем так просто
does not concern people so the war nobody
не касается людей поэтому войну никто
he does not see him, it turns out that you
его не видит он получается что вы
think that you should continue until
считаете что вы ну надо продолжать до
complete
полного
let's say the conquest of Ukraine from otherwise
скажем так покорения украины от иначе
this will cause a crisis in the middle of the Russian
это вызовет кризис середине российской
federation yes I think the following is what
федерации да я считаю следующее что
first any unfinished war or
первое любая неоконченная война или
trying to stop it right now
попытка остановить его прямо сейчас
will lead duck series of crisis in russia
приведет дак серии кризиса в россии
it is almost certain that here either
почти однозначно что здесь либо не
it was necessary to fit in, but once it formed
влезает надо было но раз образовалась
such a situation when politicians failed
такая ситуация когда политики не сумели
agree and the war has already begun
договориться и началась война уже других
there are no options here, sorry.
вариантов нет здесь ну извините это
sounds rude but here you are or we are
грубо звучит но здесь или вы нас или мы
you
вас
no well i'm basically [ __ ] figuratively because
нет ну я основах охуенная образно потому
that everything is so day 2 i happened when me
что все так дне 2-я произошло когда меня
they call me a katsap, I also answer
называют кацапом я тоже в ответ
asks look good
спрашивает а вот смотрите хорошо
it turns out now I'm your position that is
получается сейчас я вашу позицию то есть
you have to fight because if you
надо воевать потому что если вы
stop there russia conditionally so
остановитесь там россии условно так
fall apart so there will be turmoil crisis you
развалится так будет смута кризисе ты
then look, I will say it straight and I will
дальше смотрите я скажу прямо и я это
opinion heard really heard from
мнение слышал действительно слышал от
many
многих
what if we stop you don't
что если мы остановимся вы не
stop where are we going
остановитесь а куда мы пойдем
please start from what to me
пожалуйста начиная от того что мне
everyone is clear chat roulette is not
каждый понятно chat roulette не
indicator is absolutely correct but
показатель на абсолютно верно но
change public opinion forever
изменить общественное мнение всегда
can i each probably 2 chat
можно мне каждый наверное 2 chat
roulette kiosk telling what cuba is
roulette киоск рассказывать что куба это
ukraine historically given historically
украина исторически данного исторически
Kuban never settled under it
кубань никогда не по заселению под ней
hiding one thing now we i don't know
скрывался одно сейчас мы я не знаю
real people who would go
реальных людей которые бы пошли
to win back why, that is, we have neither
отвоёвывать зачем то есть у нас нет ни
docking us may be different circle
стыковаться нас может быть разные круг
communication is how we talk to one
общения это как мы разговариваем с одним
man talk says here u
человеком разговаривать говорит вот у
you there back and forth there over there
вас там туда-сюда там вот там
politically show you brainwashed
политически шоу вы промытыми мозгами
group you have propaganda to explain to me
группу у вас пропаганду мне объяснять
the news already has its own propaganda
новость уже есть своя пропаганда она
quite in my opinion very propaganda
вполне на мой взгляд пропаганда очень
she is good in ukraine is well developed there
хорошая она в украине хорошо развита там
the whole hardware does not work perfectly
целый аппаратно не работает прекрасно
works, that is, these people are not in vain
работает то есть эти люди не зря
get money they work well then
получают деньги они хорошо работают то
there is precisely the information war Ukraine
есть именно информационную войну украина
leads superb new win i
ведет превосходно новые выигрываем я
I think that the information war is here
считаю что информационную войну вот
you just need to take it and see how it is
нужно просто брать и смотреть как это
it happened like this one, roughly speaking
произошло как вот этот вот грубо говоря
how information isolation was formed
как образовалась информационной изоляции
what methods were used it's all necessary
какие методы применялись это все нужно
he won’t have time to disassemble them about the Kuban, here
разбирать их не успеет насчет кубани вот
Do you believe that the potential of Ukraine
вы верите что потенциал украины
offensive potential
наступательный потенциал
such that we can climb into the Kuban here
такое что мы сможем полезть в кубань вот
this time the authors for what we need this
это раз авторы для для чего нам вот это
we represent the entire population of the Kuban
все население кубани вы представлять мы
with these contradictions that we have
с этими противоречиями которые у нас
we still need to eat there in the east
есть там на востоке нам еще надо
deal like this, and we are still from the Kuban
разбираться так а мы еще с кубани
look you don't even have to climb on
смотрите не обязательно даже лезть на
Kuban to Kuban as you wish
кубани на кубань как хотите
I think the situation is not easy
ситуация на мой взгляд она непростая она
difficult on multifactorial i.e. the first
сложно на многофакторная то есть первое
if we stop now the first thing is
если мы сейчас остановимся первое это
lead to with girl inside and
приведет к с девушка внутри страны и
because it is declared purpose it is not
потому что заявлено цели оно не
fulfilled it's an internal political crisis
выполнено это внутриполитический кризис
Definitely 80% of the country's population
однозначно 80 процентов населения страны
won't accept it they won't go on report back
не примет это они не пойдут на доложите
pumped up even they should the question is not
накачали даже они должны вопрос не в том
that they were pumped with the question that everything is not
что их накачали вопросом что все не
they will understand why they started then and for
поймут а для чего тогда начинали и для
Why why did people die, that is, people
чего почему погибали люди то есть люди
ready to take some losses
готовы принять какие-то потери какие-то
but the victims
но жертвы
if there is a certain result
если есть определенный результат
if this result is not present, it will be Olya
если этого результата нет это будет оля
Russo-Japanese war in 4 years why
русско-японская война за 4 года к чему
she led basically everyone remembers i would
она привела в принципе все помнят я бы
we respectively this is the first second this
мы соответственно это первое второе это
what if we stop like I said
то что если остановимся мы как я сказал
don't stop you're potentially base
не остановитесь вы это потенциально базы
nato i don't say that the bases of the item
нато я не говорю что базах пункт
home base in ochakov was not the base i
базирования в очакове был это не база я
I agree the base point in Ochakovo is
согласен пункт базирования в очакове это
not the base is complete but this is the point
не база полноценно но это пункт
home base and she tara it
базирования и она тарский это
potentially carrying out developed flights
потенциально проведение развит полетов
it's potentially many of these things that
это потенциально многие эти вещи которые
extremely unpleasant, in principle, affect
крайне неприятные в принципе влияют на
security is directly possible
безопасность напрямую это возможна
supply of anti-missile systems
поставка противоракетных систем
even closer a thousand kilometers of crises
еще ближе на тысячу километров кризисов
if you watch or if you watch this
если смотреть или если смотреть это
NATO weapons that we had before
вооружение нато которые у нас было до
the beginning of this war and now now we
начала этой войны и сейчас сейчас нам
began to transmit, that is, it turns out
начали передавать то есть получается
the stated goals, on the contrary, I will not determine
заявленные цели наоборот уже не определю
to
к
the situation is what it is now what if
ситуация в том что это сейчас вот если
we'll take the cat operation after all
мы возьмем кошку операция все-таки
started not in order to war operation
начата не для того чтобы война операция
it doesn't matter to me it doesn't matter
неважно мне не принципиально
started in order to finish it
начата для того чтобы ее закончить то
is to achieve the goals then not
есть достичь поставленных целей тогда не
what is being delivered to you now
принципиально что поставляют вам сейчас
the end result is important
важен конечный результат ну для
Russian leadership is there for
российского руководства там для
leadership of the Russian army
руководства российской армии важного
ready to deliver something now in principle
готов что-то поставлять сейчас принципе
purple though that's one of those deliveries that I
фиолетово хотя вот из тех поставок что я
should just remark the air i even
следует просто ремарка воздух я даже
I don't see much point in discussing
дискутировать особо смысла не вижу не
especially large deliveries and I would say
особо большие поставки и я бы сказал
some european citizens just
некоторые граждане из европы просто
frankly, you have a speaker well and up
откровенно по у вас динамик ну и до
the Germans the Germans are so with him, but maman came in
немцы немцы так у него но маман зашел
quote we all understand from you mcs
цитата мы все понимаем из тебя mcs
sun and company three d great that is
солнце и компании три д здорово то есть
respectively
соответственно
it doesn't matter what they supply now
не принципиально что поставляют сейчас
if the goal of the drill has reached a good look
если цели бур достиг хорошо смотреть
then if in your opinion the target
тогда если вот по вашему мнению целевые
goals was this phenomenon of the finalization of this
целями был этот феномен финализации этой
operations then why activate office
операции тогда почему activate office
it was more logical to take everything, and therefore
логичнее все надо было брать и потому
what is the political leadership there i
что там политическое руководство там я
I can only honestly guess the date
могу только предположить честно дата
I have your guess
вашего предположения у меня
the assumption is that the creature is like
предположение следующее что существо как
for a and plan b if there was no plan b
по а так и план б если плана б не было
although judging by because what is happening now in
хотя судя потому что происходит сейчас в
there was a plan b and it is now being implemented mine
план б был и он сейчас реализуется мое
personal opinion next i.e.
личное мнение следующая то есть
decided to start like this having a few
решили начать вот так имея несколько
ways out of the situation, but as usual they draw
выходов из ситуации но как обычно рисуют
business to process what that is if here
бизнес к процесс какой то есть если вот
so it goes then do so if so then so
так пойдет то делаем так если так то так
accordingly, this was a fork then
соответственно вот эта была развилка то
there were led troops
есть вели войска
Roughly speaking, they were preparing there
дошли грубо говоря там там готовили
irpen butch here in those parts, respectively
ирпень буча вот в те края соответственно
stuck in a certain line of defense
уперлись в определенную линию обороны
I suspect they realized that breaking through it is
подозреваю поняли что проламывать ее это
it means that the fire corridors just need
значит просто нужно огневым коридорам
demolish all volumes two or three wide
сносить все тома ширину два-три
kilometers, that is, to make great
километра то есть делать великой
patriotic war version 2 while being done on
отечествен война версия 2 а делается на
it's not, i suspect it's not
это нет я подозреваю нет не то
Russian society is not ready to accept
российское общество не готово принять на
the current moment she is ready to accept what
текущий момент она готова принять то что
let's try to explain the situation
ну скажем попробуй объяснить ситуацию
if there is a house from this house they shoot at
если стоит дом из этого дома стреляют на
relatively speaking on the Russian tank and
условно говоря по российскому танку и
Russian tank destroys the house in response and
российский танк в ответ уничтожает дом и
some civilian is dying there, let's say
там гибнет какой-то мирный житель скажем
so but a Russian was shot from the house
так но из дома стреляли российского
society is now ready to accept this
общества сейчас готова это принять вот
just in this form only in this
именно в таком виде только в таком
context if, respectively, the military
контексте если же соответственно военной
come out and say so we need
выйдет и скажет значит так нам нужно
lay a three-kilometer strip here
здесь проложить трёхкилометровый полосу
continuous fire damage to attack
сплошного огневого поражения наступать
we will be behind a rotten shaft exclusively and
мы будем за гнилым валом исключительно и
we don't care what is called who is where
нам по хрену что называется кто там где
there that there just attacked there
там что там как раз напали там
we do not use adjustable ammunition
корректируемой боеприпасы не используем
if we do not use what is called
кабы не используем мы не что называется
holy cast iron in the bubble in all this in
святым чугуне в бабле во все это в
stone age during the week what's there
каменный век в течение недели что там
living beginning becomes near Mariupol
живого начала становится под мариуполем
did accepted Russian society
таки сделали принял российское общество
sorry let's talk a bit later
извините давайте чуть позже про
mariupol as im just keep in mind
мариуполь как им просто имей в душе
Russian live and I have another
российском прожить и у меня есть другое
opinion on this matter so let's
мнение по этому поводу поэтому давайте
let's do it in terms of the scale of destruction
давайте так по масштабам разрушений так
we hatch or was just that too come on
мы люк или была как раз та тоже давай
let's just a little bit later I just
давайте чуть чуть чуть позже я просто
I beg
прошу
well, I'll agree and then we can promo reel
ну я договорю а потом можем promo reel
asked a question and its home and just not
задали вопрос и его домой и просто не
just passing the question what happened under
просто передача вопрос что произошло под
Kyiv what will happen than lower and Sumy
киевом что произойдет чем ниже и сумская
st of the Sumy region, respectively, is
ул сумской области соответственно это
the first second when they realized that it was possible
первое второе когда поняли что возможно
that resistance she is not on option but
что сопротивление она не по варианту а
according to option b, that is, we have option
по варианту b то есть мы имеем вариант
not the Crimean resistance where there 85
не крымского сопротивления где там 85
percent of militants go to
процентов воинствующих переходят на
then serves on the side of the Russian army in
сторону российской армии служит потом в
her a we have option b when they don’t pass
ней а имеем вариант b когда не переходят
or goes to someone not at all well
либо переходит к кому-то вообще не ну
a vanishing amount of miserable then
исчезающим количестве мизерным то
accordingly, option b enters with us
соответственно вступает вариант б у нас
there is a front real background high-grade
есть фронт настоящий фон полноценный
big
большой
1600 kilometers of front in order to
1600 километров фронта для того чтобы
it is trite to keep him, and at that moment I
его банально удержать а на тот момент я
I thought they chatted one and a half thousand or
считал поболтали полторы тысячи то ли
one thousand six hundred kilometers of front in
тысячи шестьсот километров фронта в
peak value standard as far as i
пиковом значение норматив насколько я
remember the great patriotic war is 40
помню великой отечественной войны это 40
kilometers per division, respectively, I
километров на дивизию соответственно я
military military no well it has
не военный военные нет ну это имеет
a lot of these I'm a little bit historically
много вот этих я немножко исторически
that 40 divisions is roughly 400,000
той 40 дивизий это грубо говорят 400000
this war which was 70 years old
эта война которая была 70 лет совсем
other technique
другая техника
fundamentally
принципиально
these bp do not weigh
не весят эти bp
well developed very different action
хорошо развит совсем по-другому действие
the same absolutely universe once intelligence
той же абсолютно вселенную раз разведкой
intelligence principle in action on the battlefield
разведка принцип в действии на поле боя
didn't change my mind don't give me why
не изменился по уму не дают мне почему
then you had to run cheers now
тогда надо было бежать ура сейчас такого
no exactly the same run exactly the same
нет ровно так же бегут ровно также
storm the rune also beat the only thing
штурмуют руна также бьют единственно что
there is no solid front because there is no force
фронта сплошного нет потому что силы не
those if you put the army at 23
те если бы вы ставили армия в 23
million he was the answer put the army in
миллиона ему был ответ выставили армию в
23 million believe we would have
23 миллиона поверьте у нас был бы
solid front and there would be attacks through
сплошной фронт и были бы атаки через у
you both sides so we have an army
вас обеих сторон так у нас армия
we have small fronts of such a continuous
маленькие у нас фронта такого сплошного
no otherwise yes we would have
нет в противном случае да мы бы имели
these cheers attack us I would say front
вот эти ура атаки нас я бы сказал фронта
so rolling closer to civil war
такой подвижной ближе гражданской войне
that's what was the 20th century at the beginning so
вот которая была 20 веке в начале так
respectively, they understood that 1600
вот соответственно поняли что 1600
kilometers we simply do not have the strength to
километров у нас просто нет сил для
keeping a full-fledged of these 1600 troops
удержания полноценного этих 1600 войска
took streamed the front and began to conduct
отвели стримили фронт и начали проводить
operation according to option b, that is, the first
операцию по варианту б то есть первое
this is Donbass, this is the environment of the group
это донбасс это окружение группировки
chipping there in small pieces
откалывания там небольшими кусочками
through popasnuyu raisins and so on like that
через изюм попасную и так далее как то
so this is my personal opinion
так вот это мое личное мнение что
happened well let's say then let's say
произошло хорошо допустим тогда допустим
if there's some kind of sleep all on the pulley
если там какой-то до сна все на шкив
I'll have to take then it turns out I don't
придется брать тогда получается я не
I know the goals specifically what goals
знаю цели конкретно какие цели
set what they are going to take
поставлены что там собираются брать
maybe no one is going to take them
может быть их никто брать не собирается
want to stay there
хотят остановиться исключительно там
one
одно
say this, but Ukraine will not surrender to
сказать это но украина же не сдастся на
Zelinsky will stay, look, we are with you
зелинский останется смотрите мы с вами
we believe that Ukraine will not surrender based on
считаем что украина не сдастся исходя из
the current situation, the whole problem is that
текущей ситуации вся проблема в том что
changes dynamically, for example without
динамически меняется например без того
what I see I count a few telegrams
что вижу я я считаю несколько телеграмм
channels including pro-Ukrainian to wonderful
канала включая проукраинские чтобы чудно
to at least see some
чтобы хотя бы видеть некий
alternative view from ukraine
альтернативный взгляд со стороны украины
it's just at least the brain to work
это просто хотя бы мозг чтобы работал
at least somehow it's not because we have there
хоть как то это не потому что у нас там
bad then I drove it absolutely it's simple
плохие то загнал я абсолютно это просто
interesting to even compare to see what
интересно даже сравнивать смотреть что
where how did it appear who interprets how
где как появилась кто как трактует
just from the Ukrainian article you are reading
просто из украинских статейка вы читаете
listen dynamically changing moo
слушайте динамически меняется му
stable remains until only dust
стабильно остается пока только труха
the spirit of Ukraine, here it is for already
духа украина вот и она на протяжении уже
a month and a half I have here constantly
полутора месяцев у меня вот постоянно
the rest appear when they fail
остальные появляются они когда сбоить
everything starts that is from except the spirit and
начинают все то есть от кроме духа и
analysts they just where they are they on you
аналитики они просто где они они на вас
this is a news channel and me for me
это новостной канал а мне за меня
swooped in I don't need news
налетела не нужно мне интересно новости
of which I can view mods
из которых я могу с обозревать моды
without other people's these thoughts and imposition
без чужих вот этих мыслей и навязывания
something like this
чего-то вот соответственно
returning to this issue
возвращаясь к этому вопросу
it's all right now let's say
это сейчас все так вот допустим
Mariupol roughly speaking happened
мариуполе грубо говоря произошел
a certain fracture fracture here it is for me
определенный надлом перелом вот мне он
on the news clearly felt that there is
по новостям явно ощутил что есть
a certain moral breakdown
определенный моральный надлом я не
I'm talking about ammunition or something
говорю там по боеприпасам или чему-то то
eat after in mariupol
есть после того как в мариуполе
happened
произошло
surrender conditionally let's call him for
сдача в плен условно назовем его за
gate because there was far from giving up
ворот потому что там сдавался далеко не
only the basics there to see the sixth
только азов там посмотреть шестая
brigade com was the marines came out you
бригада ком была морской пехоты вышел вы
I guess I don't know what kind
массу наверно я не знаю какую то
Accordingly, I see a certain
соответственно мне виден определенный
a breakdown began to appear a lot of videos then
надлом стала появляться масса видео то
there are somehow they were not in before
есть их как-то раньше не было в
information field video teroborony about
информационном поле видео теробороны о
what was sent there under the front under the tanks
том что там послали под фронт под танки
in armament there is none there pan
в вооружения нет того нет там пан
president figure it out not yet
президент разберитесь это пока еще не
cries about what they say we all retreat
крики о том что дескать все мы отступаем
we run away, we give up, we throw our paws, but this is it
убегаем сдаемся лапы бросаем но это вот
trailer link which see that situation
звене прицепе которая вижу что ситуация
will accelerate and
будет ускоряться и
in order for me to suspect to reach
для того чтобы я подозреваю достичь
some goals of the Russian Federation I do not
каких-то целей российской федерации я не
will have to go roughly speaking to Lviv and
придется идти грубо говоря до львова а
so I would I suspect that I again no
так я бы я подозреваю что я опять же нет
I'm not a military analyst, I don't have
это я не военный аналитик я не имею
no insiders there in the Kremlin
никаких инсайдов там в кремле обычный
man i suspect it will happen
человек я подозреваю что это произойдет
when you exit it will not be about it
при выходе в не про это будет
certain psychological one
определенным психологическим одном
especially if it is taken
особенно если при этом будет взята
Odessa and Kherson sorry
одесской и херсонской пардон
Nikolaev region and there will be a call from
николаевская область и будет заход с
the other side on crooked horn from the loss
другой стороны на кривой рог от потеря
most of the millionaires if it
большей части миллионников если это
it will happen
произойдет это
basically talk about the future.
по сути говорить о дальнейшем
resistance will no longer be possible.
сопротивления уже будет невозможно
I just realized this is to watch
просто я понял вот это есть смотреть
by the way about
кстати насчет
psychological breakdown, by the way, I'm here
надлома психологической вот кстати я вот
Ukrainian information space
украинскому информационное пространство
so we have absolutely nothing
так у нас абсолютно никак
the event immediately got up they are the opposite
событие сразу встали они наоборот
heroizing so that everyone understands that their
героизируя так и все понимают что их
brought here the basis for agreements for
вывели сюда базис договоренностям для
prisoner exchange works great for you
обмена пленных у вас прекрасно работает
this information machine which is well
вот эта информационная машина которая ну
let's go right here
давайте прямо здесь вот
the machine gives absolutely incorrect
машина дает абсолютно некорректную
information not for how excellent
информацию не за насколько превосходно
this is an example for myself let's I was afraid of him
это пример себе давайте я боялась его
I agree now I can, the fact is that I
договорю теперь я смогу дело в том что я
this information catches even not from our
эту информацию цепляет даже не из наши
so I see that the shooters write that here
вот я смотрю что стрелков пишет что вот
these dnr ovsky so here are these prisoners
эти днр овский так что вот этих пленных
and call the prisoners
и зова а пленных
placed there in
поместили там в
hospital in the Nevitsky castle of these
госпиталь в невицкий замок этих
militia from there so them red cross
ополченцев оттуда так ним красный крест
there is a hand and they are preparing for the exchange, that is
рука есть и готовят к обмену то есть
there were some political
были какие-то политические
agreements on the abolition of captivity and now
договоренности об отмене плен и и вот
I like some uncle from the DPR
мне нравится с днр какой-то там дяденька
like I weigh years not in captivity but with us
типа вешу года не в плену но с нами
communicates as if we are in their captivity
общается как будто это мы у них в плену
that is, I understand you want to say I
то есть я понял вы хотите сказали я
understood a little look if I'm not that
понял мало смотрите если я это не то что
with us in a priori you stand and in general I
у нас нас in a priori стоишь и вообще я
does not serve, I pray, looks at varis when
не служит я молю смотрит варис когда
there is such a thing as we take facts on them
есть такая вещь как мы берем факты на их
facts on these facts together theory a
фактах на этих фактов вдвоем теорию а
sometimes a theory is taken and chosen
берется иногда теория и выбираются
certain facts and always very
определенные факты и всегда очень
joyfully man who builds some
радостно человек который строит какую-то
theory laptop wants to find some
теорию ноутом хочет найти некую
the regularity he is among the masses is just that
закономерность он среди массы просто вот
randomly scattered numbers always
случайно разбросанных чисел всегда
will find you the sequence he needs
найдет вас нужную ему последовательность
for example, the same shooter in
например тот же стрелков которого в
Russia now, well, in a good word, I don’t
россии сейчас ну хорошим словом я не
I know who remembers to be honest
знаю кто вспоминает честно скажем так
It's been a long time since he's raw I'll tell straight shooters
уже давно он сырья скажу прямо стрелков
probably about two months already
где-то примерно наверно месяца два уже
how they [ __ ] just like this some
как сношают просто как этого какого-то
freak honestly given if you look let's say
фрика честно данную если смотреть скажем
on
по
understanding of the military situation, he clearly
понимание военной ситуации он явно
surpasses me or you he looked at
превосходит меня или вас он смотрел на
warm he yes he can be military
греве он да он может быть военным
analysts but two things cannot be denied
аналитикам но нельзя отрицать две вещи
first shooters extremely resentful current
первая стрелков крайне обиженно текущей
the current government very seriously and
нынешнюю власть очень серьезно и
almost all of his statements that he
почти все свои заявления которые он
threw up after 14 years when he was removed
бросал после 14 года когда его убрала
the current Russian government of Donbass
действующая российская власть донбасса
it directly says that he was told that
это прямо говорит что ему сказали что
if he stays there
если он там останется
nothing good comes out of it but how
ничего хорошего из этого не полна а как
she could remove from independent
она могла убрать из независимого
states told him directly, well, according to him
государства ему прямо заявили ну по его
again, that they directly stated that
словам опять же что прямо заявили что
if he doesn't get out of there no help
если он оттуда не уйдет никакой помощи
will not turn out that is either or
оказываться не будет то есть либо либо
he dumps from the Donbass and then Russia
он сваливает с донбасса и тогда россия
provides assistance to the Donbass or he is there
оказывает помощь донбассу либо он там
remains then no help will be well and
остается то никакой помощи не будет ну и
all local citizens understanding such
все местные граждане понимая такой
the alignment, as I understand it, comrades girls on
расклад как я понимаю товарищи девки на
Strelkov was extremely requested
стрелкова крайне просили
limits yes because girkin you're done
пределы да потому что гиркин ты молодец
but we would
но нам бы
slightly different order
немножко другого порядка
so extremely while running he is not
поэтому крайне а бежим он это не
hides u repeatedly stated it in
скрывает у многократно это заявлял в
some period of time really
какой то период времени действительно
read him an interview listened to it
ему интервью читала слушал вот было
Gordon's interviews seem to be here I am named after Paul
интервью гордону кажутся вот я имени пол
on Gordon, we also have our own
на гордона у нас тоже свой какой-то
Gordon is there, respectively, gave
гордон там есть вот соответственно давал
I listened to the interview but already directly
интервью я его слушал но уже прямо
I said these interviews some of my
заявлял я этим интервью какие-то свои
there goals realize some of their own
там цели реализуют какие-то свои
political swami den I usually mean
политического свами ден я обычно к тому
what if you take the necessary facts
что да если вот взять нужные факты
turn them theory turns out theory but
включить их теории получается теория но
it is necessary to close your eyes to just a mass
это нужно закрыть глаза на просто массу
statement from the very top of the Russian
заявление самого верха российской
top politicians who were
политики самого верха которые были
very defiantly done
сделаны очень демонстративно очень
demonstratively when Anatoly Vaserman
демонстративно когда анатолий васерман
member of the State Duma
депутат государственной думы
say let's apply
заявляют что давайте применим
any law prohibiting the extradition
какой-нибудь закон запрещающий выдачу
and after that citizen volodin speaker
а после этого гражданин володин спикер
State Duma and which is very close
госдумы и который очень близок
to the president and whom let's go straight
президенту и которого давайте прямо
practically appointed speaker there
практически назначили туда спикером
when there is a head of administration here
когда есть главой администрации тут как
United Russia would have sent him
бы его послали и единая россия
supported the candidacy naturally
поддержала кандидатуру естественно
the majority elected him 2 speaker there
большинство его выбрали 2 спикером там
all that was left was to negotiate with others
оставалось только договориться с другими
parties about sharing some
партиями о том чтобы поделить какие-то
committees, but if such people declare
комитеты но если такие люди заявляют о
that no we will not issue if any
том что нет выдавать не будем если любая
in fact, an attempt to speak on a high
фактически попытка заговорить на высоком
level about what we think about the exchange
уровне о том что мы думаем об обмене
instantly causes an incredible shout
моментально вызывает невероятную окрик
top of the discharge you something is wrong there
сверху из разряда вы что-то там не так
understand it says one thing
себе поняли это говорит об одном что
no one there no one me just me just
никто там никого меня просто я просто
looked at what prices were taken out
смотрел каких вывозили цен застали в
comfortable buses, that is, obviously
комфортабельных автобусов то есть явно
not like selling buses any time as but
не как продающие автобуса any time as но
how much if the skin for these troubles
насколько если кожи за ведь эти беды
well, buses, buses, that's just
ну автобусы автобусы вот просто
army truck to army truck
армейский грузовик на армейский грузовик
maybe I even take the bus more
может в автобус больше выезжает я даже
I suspect that the bus will fit
подозреваю что автобус влезет будешь
just if you look at the rifle there
просто вот если смотреть там стрелковую
look like a phreak but I also think that
выглядите phreak но мне я тоже думаю что
he is there in something you can’t say that now
он там в чем-то нельзя говорю что сейчас
he already has a reputation flickr just
у него уже репутация flickr просто
poke that he is a phreak from those here i look
ткнуть что он phreak из тех вот я смотрю
that he criticizes so and I liked me
что он критикует так и мне нравилось мне
better fur coat you thought you were a freak and not
лучше шубе вы считали фриком так и не
wires introduced you what he is, well, I
провода внедряли вы то что он то ну я
I understand what to talk about here if
понимаю о чем говорить на вот если
not just I understand Ukrainian quite well
не просто я вполне понимаю украинский
where are you from
сами откуда у
old women almost everything is not in my opinion
старушки практически все по моему не
they do not understand Ukrainian well, and well, not everyone
плохо понимают украинский и ну не все
some fundamentally rejects well it
некоторые принципиально отторгает ну это
either something in my head or thrown from where
либо что-то в голове либо бросали откуда
by birth sense by birth well where do you live from where
родом смысле родом ну где живете откуда
your ancestors Krasnodar only said
ваши предки краснодар лишь сказали
cashier I'm just all these how to say
кассирша я просто все эти как сказать
there studi you hid didn't climb if they
там спуди вы укрыли не лез если они
never flies your ancestors from Krasnodar
never мушки ваши предки краснодар откуда
populate nick tongues so me
заселяемся ника языками так мне
wait for Krasnodar, he is generally a third
подождите краснодару он вообще на треть
while still here our ex roughly speaking
при еще здесь наш бывшая грубо говоря
the conglomerate will probably be here
конгломерат станет здесь наверное
percent if so historically follow
процентов если так исторически последить
there are almost no locals I want where yours are from
местных почти нет хочу откуда ваши
ancestors are to Krasnodar and my ancestors
предки это до краснодар а и мои предки
this is the Bryansk Oryol province if so
это брянской орловской губернии если так
well, the historical bryansk eagle is there
ну историческая брянск орел там
in general, in fact, Ukrainians are not
вообще на самом деле украинские не
understand only two categories of citizens
понимают только две категории граждан
do not specifically understand not separate
прям конкретно не понимают не отдельные
words and the general meaning of speech is either those
слова а общий смысла речи это либо те
who just doesn't want to understand
кто понимать просто не хочет ничего так
as they say it is like the same Balts
как там говорит это как те же прибалты
says we are Russians, I know well with you
говорит мы русские знаю ну с вами
we will not talk and the second is those
разговаривать не будем и второе это те
for whom for Russians for whom Russians are not
для кого для россиян для кого русские не
native example of the Tatars for him since childhood
родные пример татары для него с детства
there my mother once said in Tatar
там мама по-татарски как-то сказал
respectively for him native Tatar
соответственно для него родной татарский
for him, Russian is essentially on the second
для него русски это по сути на второй
language similar slavic hard then
язык похожих славянские тяжело тогда
I understand yes because
понимаю да потому что допустим
Belarusian and Ukrainian I understand
белорусский и украинский я понимаю
quite good czech me bad
вполне неплохо чешский мне плохо
listen to the phrase
воспринимать на слух там словосочетание
others but let's say when I read it I could
другие но допустим когда его читаю мог
forgive and the words
простить и слова вот и
I can understand
я могу понять
call move and ladies' pansky children's scrap
call ход и дамские панский детский скрап
we so on but it's all like but he without
мы так далее но это все как бы но он без
agree and almost identical yes just
согласны и почти одинаковые да просто
when it's hard to hear because
когда на слух до тяжеловато потому что
take some getting used to because it's different
нужно привыкнуть потому что по-другому
pronounced letters and combination glory is
произносится буквы и сочетание славу это
like a famous meadow
как знаменитая поляница
there is no such combination in Russian
вот в русском языке нет такое сочетание
badly pronounce
плохо произносим
you don't know what the word syktyvkar is
вы не знаете что такое слово сыктывкар
Syktyvkar we know to the city
сыктывкар знаем до города
- I just when when they shout at me
- я просто когда когда мне кричат на
position if I inflict zalevskaya
позицию я если нанесу залевская
Mari El Republic
республика марий эл
so not far away
так не отколе
interesting to me
по моему интересно
comida settle republic of komi to call
comida селиться республика коми to call
mari el that there we have only carlopa
марий эл что там у нас лишь carlopa
it seems yes or only karla this native is not
кажется да или лишь карла этом родную не
I remember, in my opinion, all the same, Carla and there
помню по моему все таки уж карла и туда
mario home dialogues 2
марио дома диалоги 2
you see got geography seedlings
вы видите получили география рассада
thank you for the heat already so thank you
спасибо вам за разгар уже так спасибо
that's how you think what all the same
вот как вот вы считаете чем все-таки
end here I bring you want
закончиться вот я приношу вы хотите
language and that it ends in victory
языка и чтобы она закончилась победой
Russia, we want the wedge to win
россии мы хотим чтоб победу клин вот по
your prediction how it will end
вашему прогнозу чем закончится
but if you somehow objectively approach
но если как-то объективно подходить к
question we inside ourselves objectively i
вопросу мы внутри себя объективно я
I see that it will not end very well
вижу что все она закончится не очень
good for the Ukrainian state in that
хорошо для украинского государства в том
in terms of what it was like before February 24
плане что каким оно было до 2 4 февраля
we are definitely not a girlfriend and the ladies are definitely not
мы уже точно не подругу и дамы точно не
well, as it will grow, but for
ну таким как будет растет а для
Russian katana ga ima geographically
российского katana ga ima территориально
and territorial r-series
а территориальном r-серии
I see that already both Kherson and part
я вижу что уже и херсонскую и часть
Zaporozhye region is precisely prepared
запорожской области точно готовят
inclusion is all, as it were, sources
включения это все как бы источников
I guess it all depends on the friend
видно все зависит наверное от товарища
God forbid, of course Zelensky, where is he
не дай господи конечно зеленского где он
decides to still go to negotiations where he
решит все таки идти на переговоры где он
decides to fix losses let's say the whole
решит фиксировать убытки скажем так весь
the new brick one is called what would it be
новом кирпичном называется как это бы
didn't sound harsh but I see that
грубовато не звучало но я вижу что
the option that
вариант о том что
at least several regions of Odessa
несколько как минимум областей одесская
Nikolaev Kherson part
николаевская херсонская часть
Zaporizhzhya, perhaps even the entire Luhansk
запорожского возможно даже вся луганская
and Donetsk and, accordingly, part
и донецкая ну и соответственно часть
border such as the Kharkov bag
пограничных таких как харьковская сумка
on the speedy budget of ukraine is ours if
на скорейшем бюджет украины наша если
Zelensky, here we are Nazis
зеленскому вот мы там нацисты
nationalists began to take and will not give
националисты стали брать и не дадим
sign here is such a capital zone
подписать вот такое капитале зона
agreement
соглашение
the point here is that I don't think that
здесь вопрос в том что я не считаю что
well, what kind of Nazis and then with a stormy
нацисты ну какой образа и тогда с бурный
image well let's not I'm of course
образ ну давайте так нет я конечно
I think that part of the population of Ukraine
считаю что часть населения украины
let's just say it suffers from a mild form
скажем так страдает легкой формы
xenophobia in the light though again also
ксенофобии в легкой хотя опять же также
I think in Russia more xenophobes go to
считаю в россии больше ксенофоб иду на
wait i think so
подождите я так же считаю что может быть
same part maybe i polls
такая же часть может быть я опросов
did not hold public opinion in both
общественного мнения не проводил в обеих
countries to understand who has more
странах чтобы понять у кого больше у
whom the sword I believe that part of the people in
кого меч я считаю что часть людей в
Russia also suffers a mild form
россии тоже страдают легкой формы
xenophobia is light and stress you no
ксенофобии легкой и подчеркиваю вас нет
we can have it, but at the same time
ее у нас могут но при этом
I think that most but this
я считаю что большая часть но это
most of the people are still
большая часть людей это все-таки по
to the principle of a hut, I’ll hide what will happen when
принципу хата скраю что когда будет
conditions deteriorate sharply
резко ухудшаться условия
vital activity
жизнедеятельности
when to give him right there if measured
когда ему давать прямо там если мерить
according to roulette, it’s generally there all the warriors
по рулетке это вообще там все воины
now everyone will run to fight us especially
сейчас побегут все воевать нам особенно
from which date and sit patriots here I am
от которой даты и сидят патриоты вот я
I think that when
думаю что когда
there will be a scrapping of the Donbass front well
произойдет слом донбасского фронта ну
it just ceases to exist
вот просто он перестанет существовать
it will be very serious
это будет очень серьезным
psychological angle and everything will start there
психологическим углом и там все начнут
develop much more rapidly
развиваться намного стремительно на
much if you think you've been through
много если вы считаете что вы пережили
the fact that the dollar is not for 8 since in
то что доллар не по 8 так как в
the fourteenth year that prices rose
четырнадцатом году что поднялись цены
in short, they temporarily lost Crimea there
что короче временно потеряли там крым
through the Donbass and this did not stop us in
через донбасс и это нас не остановило в
this
этом
some changes in the database will stop us
какие-то изменения в базе нас остановят
no one can understand that it's big
понимать могу никто что это большой
the volume of losses of material people people in
объем потерь материальных людей людях в
territories one of the problems of any even
территориях одна из проблем любой даже
the best propaganda in the classroom
самой хорошей пропаганды на классной
propaganda and now you need to blow it through your
пропагандой и вот ее нужно продуть ваш
father and definitely yes yes yes I carry I'm straight
отец и однозначно да да да я несу я прям
I do not deny it, you need to take it as
это не отрицаю ее нужно брать как
disassemble the sample clearly how would you like it
образец разбирать явно как бы вам ее
done by Western experts in your regions
делали специалисты запада у вас регионов
do not look at all of you temporary that we have
не смотрите вы все временные что у нас
something of the west we have no place of residence
что то запада у нас нет места жительства
wait for your specialists, you are missing
подождите своих специалистов вас хватает
but I follow certain techniques
но определенные методики я прослеживаю
let's just say very similar otherwise
скажем так очень похожих иначе еще
starting from iraq i.e. it's either you
начиная с ирака то есть это либо вы
borrowed the method we made yours
позаимствовали метод мы сделали ваши
professionals or anyone
специалисты либо кто-то из
high-class people, well, I shared my experience
высококлассных людей ну делился опытом я
I'm not saying that some kind of me is sitting there
не говорю что у вас там сидит какой то я
don't know there american john july the whole
не знаю там американский джон июле всей
propaganda I believe that this is rude
пропаганды я верю в том что этому грубо
adjoined yes, that is, I do not say what it is
примыкала да то есть я не говорю что это
some American rising propaganda
какие-то американцу ростом пропаганду
develop yes your citizens do it
развивать да это делают ваши граждане
absolutely right what I say
абсолютно верно я говорю что
certain methods of experience are nothing
определенные методики опыта это ничего
there is nothing wrong with that, but if you have experience
плохого в этом нет но если есть опыт
there is already someone who did something similar
есть уже кто-то делал что-то подобное
why not take beer
почему пиво не взять на вооружение
okay he'll take the russian army chu
нормально он возьмем российскую армию чу
reinvent the wheel how would they system
изобретать велосипед как бы они систему
layers but clothes this 7 levels model
слоев но одежду этот 7 уровней модель
they just took a sax from the american army
просто взяли с американской армии сакса
took and copied what's wrong with it already
взяли и скопировали чего плохого она уже
as if worked out everything is fine here
как бы отработаны все отлично вот
accordingly, the whole problem of propaganda
соответственно вся проблема пропаганды
even the best is that when
даже самые лучшие то в том что когда
the results are getting too
результаты становится слишком
parents can talk about some victories
родители можно говорить о неких победах
we can say that we are there
можно говорить о том что там мы
exterminate the front here we do it
истребляем фронт здесь мы делаем это
here we do that but when will
здесь мы делаем то но когда будет
Donbass has been completely surrendered, roughly speaking
полностью сдан донбасс ну грубо говоря
will either be forced to withdraw troops or
вынужден будет либо отойти войска либо
will not fall into the boilers it will be, let's say
не попадут в котлы это будет скажем так
military solution to the situation to explain it
военное решение ситуации объяснить это
it's going to be really hard
будет уже ну категорически сложно
people believe people believe in accurate Kherson
люди-то верят люди верят в точных херсон
will be returned in a month or two people
будет возвращен через месяц-два люди
believe in what it is if it is not
верят в то что это если этого не
will happen there will be questions
произойдёт начнутся вопросы есть вы
think that when you are already from the caste or
считаете что когда уже вы из касты или
under sorry sorry sorry yes say a
под извините извини извините да говорю а
further will be approximately as it was in
дальше будет примерно как было в
the Soviet Union, you told us that
советском союзе вы нам рассказывали вот
this didn't happen much
это вот этого не случилось значительно
we were lied to
нам врали
I always want to understand how Russia does not
я вот всегда хочу понять как россия не
they see us, that is, we are already under here
видят нас то есть у нас тут уже под
troops were stationed in Kyiv and we somehow
киевом стояли войска и мы как-то
let's say they didn't break like that, but if
скажем не сломались так но вот если
somewhere to push us away in the Donbass
где-то нас там отодвинуть на донбассе
everything seems to be broken
все как бы сломать не
understand the point is that before you stood
понимаете дело в том что до вы стояли
there and well declared to you
там и вам ну декларировались
certain victories phantom cues yet
определенные победы призрак киева еще
something they declared and
что то какие то они декларировались а
then there was a positive result and
потом был позитивный результат и
words about the ghost of Kyiv and other things they
слова про призрака киева и прочего они
the Russians were confirmed, the Russians left
подтвердились русские ушли российские
troops took the ears victory let me straight
войска взяли ушки победа давайте прямо я
frankly, a defensive battle for
прямо скажу оборонительное сражение за
kyiv ukraine won so without a hitch
киев украина выиграла так без обиняков
stage what is it and if one one army
этапе что такого и если одно одно войско
roughly speaking one army left 2 left
грубо говоря одна армия ушла 2 осталось
means a defensive battle was
значит оборонительное сражение было
won and
выиграно и
yes, you can say it again
да можно сейчас еще раз говорить там
there was no goal to storm and I don’t know the other
цели штурмовать не было и прочая не знаю
I only then at the entrance but
я лишь то при входе но
here is the opposite
здесь обратная ситуация
report that you win
докладывают о том что вы выигрываете
win win all good all
выигрываете выигрываете все хорошо все
fine now here we are here we are
отлично сейчас вот мы вот-вот еще
a little bit and we are there in the Kursk region
чуть-чуть и мы там в курскую область
let's go in conditionally saying that I'm exaggerating I'm
войдем условно говоря это я утрирую я
I exaggerate I exaggerate the 3rd I'm sorry
утрирую я утрирую 3-го извините
sweet there will be in the Kursk region
сладкие там будут в курской области это
all plans with test before work on here
все планы с тестом до работы по вот
the situation is that they often declare victory
ситуация в том что часто заявляют победы
I even see the dust on Orestovich
я вижу даже вот по орестович трухи по
tapes that all of these are negative
лентам что все вот эти вот негативные
results they all try somehow
результаты они все пытаются как-то
smooth out if it's too obvious
сгладить если будет слишком явно
negative result promised positive
негативный результат обещали позитивный
it can be almost one hundred percent
это может а практически по сто процентов
a simple one will happen, for example not
произойдет простой вот например не
understanding if they could not take Kharkov
понимая если не смогли взять харьков
which is 20 kilometers from the border with
который там 20 километров от границы с
him with provision with all this so that
ним с обеспечением с этим всем так то
how then the Russian army is going
как тогда российская армия собирается
take the Dnieper there Zaporozhye Nikolay
взять там днепр там запорожье николай
I can take 4 ha already explains them
мне может взять 4 га их уже объясняет
they were under the most nikolai look who
они были под самым николай смотрите кто
said something kharkov
сказал что-нибудь харькова
no, but how can I get it, I'm just looking now
нет а как возьму вот я просто сейчас ищу
give like Mariupol exactly the same now
давать как мариуполь ровно также сейчас
intensified
еще усилилась
cook before attacked the ferret me
готовят раньше нападали на хорька мне
no lines of defense were prepared
подготовлены не было ни рубежей обороны
so on the knee white was made of you
так на коленке белым делалась из вы
think that it will be possible with less blood
считаете что можно будет меньшей кровью
go there
зайти туда
I will calculate what to attack Kharkov
я рассчитаю что наступать на харьков
let's just say don't become having on your left
скажем так не стали имея у себя на левом
flank of a large group in the Donbass
фланге крупную группировку в донбассе
you decided to liquidate first and then
вы решили сначала ликвидировать а потом
if this group departs in the same
если эта группировка отойдет в тот же
the most they wouldn’t give me even on earth
самый то мне бы хоть на земле не дадут
move away just give this boilers boilers and
отойти просто дайте этом котлы котлы и
horror good and last then question 2
ужаса хорошо и последнее тогда вопрос 2
I'm holding now, but if, for example, all the same
держу сейчас а если например все-таки
Ukraine will win and who do you think will become with
украина победит а кто по-вашему станет с
Russia is by his disintegration of the state
россией это по его распад государства
one hundred percent if you consider confusion
сто процентов если считаетесь смута
so so
настолько такая
no one look well military way
никто смотрите ну военным способом
win now in my opinion ukraine
победить сейчас на мой взгляд украины
there are no options for the military factory
вариантов нет ни на завод военным
so I believed that I was extrapolating that
поэтому верилось что я экстраполирую что
if there is no military way to win
если нет военных способом победить
the meaning of sleep when we can conditionally
значение сна когда мы можем условно
saying lose is go for some
говоря проиграть это пойти на какие-то
arrangements that people will accept
договоренности которые люди воспримут
like a loss and for example what
как проигрыш а например какие
agreements can be a loser
договоренности могут быть проигрыш но
look, I'll tell you directly when this is
смотрите я вам прямо скажу когда вот это
there was a round of negotiations
был раунд переговоров
even before the meeting of Belarus
еще еще до когда совещались белоруссии
need to be there on TV with each other
надо там по телевизору друг с другом
talking rudely over there
разговаривали грубо говоря там через
I saw this on the internet
интернет я видел вот это вот
public opinion is very
общественное мнение вокруг себя очень
furiously and everyone held their fingers to these
яростно и все держали пальцев чтобы эти
negotiations just failed
переговоры просто провалились
because Russian public opinion on
потому что общественное мнение россии на
that moment any result well if
тот момент любой результат ну если бы
came out said we agreed on something
вышли сказали мы договорились на то
no longer occurs does not spread
больше не наступает не распространяется
ukraine is a neutral state there it is
украина нейтральное государство там это
everyone would say next something like that
все бы сказали следующих примерно ну так
husband in Minsk agreed nothing
мужа в минске договаривались ничего
no good came of it for the third time
хорошему не привело в этом в третий раз
agreed on Minsk three, probably you
договорились на минск три наверное вы
idiots why do we need such idiots in
идиоты зачем нам такие идиоты в
government so everyone kept their fingers crossed
правительстве поэтому все держали пальцы
about the fact that my environment has at least
о том что у моего окружения по крайней
at least by the way, would you put what he writes
мере кстати вы бы поставили то что пишет
shooters we can take maybe not well I
стрелков можем взять может быть нет ну я
don't you live you believe swore it
не вы живете вы считаете клялись это
freaks I'm talking about what he has
фриков я говорю о том что у него
reputation dinner game what he says no
репутация ужин игра что он говорит не
which in my opinion are things well from a position
которые на мой взгляд вещи ну с позиции
man offended modern nail
человека обиженного современно гвоздь
even if, for example, Ukraine beats back
даже если если например украина отобьет
there in a military lipolytic way
там военными липолитическим способом тот
same Kherson it will be considered for
же самый херсон это будет считаться для
Russian defeats for overall hairstyles
россии поражения для в общем причёскам
the question is that even if ukraine is to be
вопрос в том что если даже украина to be
your hips one the question is how
your hips one вопрос в том что как
the operation ends
закончится сама операция
explain even with our enough
объяснить даже с нашей достаточно
crooked propaganda and comrade
кривоватые пропаганды и товарищ
konashenkov the loss of all the amount will be able to
конашенков потери всех сумма сумеет
enough to remember that palmyra
достаточно вспомнить того чтобы пальмиру
that you never know twice while the operation in
что мало ли два раза при этом операция в
Syria is basically still wearing
сирии в принципе до сих пор носить
finish but there is a problem with idlib
закончим но там проблема с идлибом
shakes now the second front after all the same
качает сейчас второй фронт после все же
transfer our troops there too, well
перекидывать наши войска тоже туда ну
there's not quite a second front and leg
там не совсем второй фронт и ногу
slowly but for us it is 7 what for russia
медленно а для нас это 7 что для россии
it's all on the second front
это все на второй фронт
I have to delay I don’t know two
приходится оттягивать не знаю две
squadrons of these flights squadron
эскадрильи этих полетов эскадрилья
bombers but look good for you
бомберов но смотрите по хорошо для вас
let there be hosts for you
для вас пусть будет саваофа
the number of people involved in explicit
количество задействованных на явных
Russian crew important too now
русски экипажа важно тоже сейчас
shortage of pilots
нехватка летчиков
that he follows recently this
что он следует недавно этот
60 five years some wagner already
60 пять лет некоторые вагнер уже
recruiting already and why wrote signed
набирают уже и почему написал подписал
Putin's show is there after 60 how many years
путин шоу же там после 60 ли скольки лет
you can watch the feed of the deceased at home
можно смотреть корма погибшую дома у
he had a difficult relationship with
него сложные взаимоотношения были с
Ministry of Defense
министерством обороны
so broke but he really was
так разбил но он действительно был
extremely talented pilot
крайне талантливым летчиком
really this is a pilot from God
действительно это пилот от бога такие
talk but usually so gifted and
говорят но обычно такие одаренные и
talented people they are very well difficult
талантливые люди они очень ну сложно
befriend the system with anyone so I
дружат системы с любой поэтому я
I suspect that he did not contract
подозреваю что он контракта и не стал
sign the armed forces went
подписывать вооруженными силами пошел
Precisely roughly speaking conditionally in dude as well
именно грубо говоря условно в чувак а
because we made it easier and easier for me
потому что мы так было проще и легче я
I would not say about some kind of shortage in our country
бы не говорю о некой нехватки у нас
by the way, not far from here this flight
кстати недалеко здесь этот летное
school
училище
cattle they don't have an accelerated release
у скотный у них нет ускоренного выпуска
in general walnut normal standard set
вообще орех обычный стандартный набор
it makes sense to produce haylage sorties that's how much
смысл выпускать сенаж вылеты вот сколько
I monitor your these continents here
я мониторе ваших этих континентов сюда
were you not trying so hard to line
были ты не делаю так стараются линии
the front did not raise ours after all
фронта не поднять наши по все таки
well now work chase by or is it
хорошо сейчас работы погони по или это
I can get it again I can I don't
можно добыть снова повторим я могу я не
I will say this with this statement
скажу так я с этим утверждением
I don't agree at all
нисколько не согласен можно долго
discuss therefore and belt equipped when
дискутировать поэтому и поясе есть если
find together again yes let's go on the second
найду вместе снова да пойдем по второму
circle about the military is not about us here
кругу про военный не про нас здесь
the principle that ours still fly on
принцип того что наши все-таки летают на
attack and even su-34, and although this is not
штурмовку и даже су-34 и хотя это не
quite their task is working behind the lines
совсем их задачу работают за линии
front and at the same time successful yes but their
фронта и при этом успешным да но их
periodically knock down this texture here
периодически сбивают эту фактуру здесь
there is a problem precisely in focality and
есть проблема именно в очаговость и
it is not yours as a single system
вашего она не как единая система
Let's just say one of the principles of the military
скажем так один из принципов военный
analyst this story is just that
аналитик вот эта история всего лишь это
just stories if you study history
всего лишь истории если изучаешь историю
the second world war is
второй мировой войны приходится
clarify certain terms
определенные термины для себя прояснять
otherwise not just nothing tore me apart
иначе не просто нечем разорвал мне
it seems to still design the second
кажется все таки проектировать вторую
world war
мировую войну
she wasn't technically the same
она технически было совсем не такая как
modern war listen to my private
современная война слушать мое личное
the opinion that war does not change
мнение что война она не меняется
start oms the invention of the spear in essence
начинают омс изобретение копья по сути
principles of warfare remain the same
принципы военных действий остаются одни
and the same things all this period when
и те же вещи весь этот период когда
once a piggy bank flew to you, and so it
когда-то вам прилетала копилок а так он
an artillery shell arrives
прилетает артиллерийский снаряд всего
they just don’t know how to extrapolate their own
лишь ну не знают экстраполировать свое
let's say so surprisingly from a distance
скажем так на удивление с дистанции
defeat relatively speaking 25 meters
поражения условно говоря 25 метров
with a dart there and a crowbar yes distance
дротиком там и ломом да дистанции
defeat in food kilometers with the principle
поражения в пищу километров при принцип
move the same one and the fire of the enemy
один и тот же отодвинь и огнём врага
away
подальше
battlefield integration long arm
интеграция на поле боя длинная рука
logistics all
логистика все
you need these from Konashenkov's place
эти вас надо от места конашенкова
put
ставить
more sure then he tells
более уверен затем он рассказывает
quite sure in this regard, well done she
вполне уверен в этом плане молодец она
filmed flowers other guys fisherman
снимала цветам другие ребята рыбак
said the Persians will at times conti it already
сказал персов будем в разы conti это уже
1:20 all of you somehow write it down is you
1:20 все вы как-то это записывать это ты
wrote and I'm a blogger
записывал а я блогер
who I don't cut that is me so
кто я не вырезаю то есть я так
post conversations before with Russian then
выкладывай разговоры до с русским то
have fun with you covered i think
есть интересно с вами покрыли я думаю
will be
будет
I will say that there are just a lot of people
скажу ну что куча народа есть просто
such frenzied arches of ignatiy durov are here
такие бешеные арки игнатий дурова тут
be the first to know from all sides
первыми знаете со всех сторон такое
now what is shouting from our side
сейчас что с нашей стороны кричат
krymnash that I go to chat roulette
крымнаш что я захожу в чат-рулетку
someone shouts immediately there glory to ukraine
кто-то кричит сразу же там слава украине
and for a long time they begin to water it I would
и давно поливать начинают это я бы
said there are enough morons everywhere not just
сказал дебилов везде хватает не просто
that's interesting to know that's how we are here
вот интересно знать вот как мы вот
I perceive my hryvnia as an enemy
гривен свой я воспринимаю как врага вы
me, too, like Prague, but the picture is dear to me
меня тоже как прага но картина родная я
you as an enemy were not perceived well as
вас как врага не воспринимали хорошо как
a citizen of a country like I perceive
гражданина страны вроде я воспринимаю
like a because
как а потому что
I understand to please you because Russia
я понимаю вас радовать потому что россия
just agree the situation is what I'm not
просто договорю ситуация какая вот я не
I perceive at the moment and big
воспринимаю на текущий момент и большая
some Russian citizens do not perceive
часть граждан россии не воспринимает
the state of ukraine as an enemy
государство украина как врага
like no enemy can be like
как никого противника может быть как
there is some kind of enemy like this
врага вот есть какая-то вот такая вот
the difference is why this war is not for us
разница почему для нас эта война не
has now become something personal for you, we
стало сейчас чем-то личным для вас мы
enemy because for you it is personally with you
враг потому что для вас это лично у вас
mobilization people go to the front die
мобилизация люди идут на фронт погибают
your loved ones at the front and not pressed on
ваши близкие на фронте и не нажатии на
civilians die flies neighbors neighbor
гражданке погибают улетает соседи сосед
I'm right to the neighbor, he said let's say
соседу я именно прав он говорил допустим
mobilized neighbor went to the front died
мобилизовали соседа ушел на фронт погиб
this is personal this is the enemy we have now
это личная это враг у нас свою сейчас
contract army
контрактная армия
look, I'll say this
смотрите вот скажу что
you so here's your interests included losing
вы так вот ваши интересы входит проигрыш
my country
моей страны
static captures and military way
статические захваты и военным путем
so you have an enemy identified that is
поэтому вы есть враг определили то есть
a few for you on my enemy i'm with that
несколько для вас на мой враг я с этим
not so here he took to the front from me
не так вот он взяли на фронт от меня
look, I do not argue with this thesis, but
смотрите я с этим тезисом не спорю но
just like an enemy, you’ll directly ask
именно как враг вот прямо спросишь
Ukraine is an enemy, I'm not allowed among
украина враг я вот не допустим среди
I don’t see my surroundings so that someone
своего окружения не вижу чтобы кто-то
I was able to answer yes, this is the enemy at war with him
смог ответить да это враг на с ним воюет
there is a fine line here and
вот здесь определенная тонкая грань и
Now, if we have conscripts going to the front
вот если у нас на фронт пойдут срочники
that is, ordinary people will go mobilization
то есть обычные люди пойдет мобилизация
conscripts will go here, the same one will come
пойдет срочники здесь наступит та самая
thing when Ukraine becomes an enemy
вещь когда украина станет врагом
will be much worse
останется намного страшнее
the game is simple if 147 million start
игра просто если 147 миллионов начнут
perceive Ukraine as an enemy precisely
воспринимать украину как врага именно
that needs to be wiped off the face of the earth
которую нужно стереть с лица земли это
I'll be scared to tell you honestly I'm up to
будет страшно я вам честно говоря я до
I didn't want this to happen, but now
такого не хотел чтобы пошло а сейчас
how many millions do I perceive
сколько миллионов так воспринимаю
as an enemy I think I perceive
как врага я думаю воспринимаю
really a small part well if not
действительно небольшая часть ну если не
take chatroulette as an indicator of some
брать чат-рулетку как показатель некой
really it has a lot of pins
действительно ним пинов достаточно много
who get drunk there conditionally speaking in
которые там нажираются условно говоря в
Friday morning and declare someone there
пятницу с утра и декларируют кто-то там
glory to ukraine someone glory to russia and
слава украине кто-то слава россии и
it would be interesting to record later
вот интересно бы удалось потом запись
there in a month or two to see how
там через месяц-два посмотреть как вот
these are our predictions
эти наши прогнозы
let's for fun y'all let's
давайте для интереса вы все давайте
good day to you too already trinity trinity
хорошего дня вам тоже уже троица троица
it will be a holiday from you see yes but I
это от вас будет праздник видите да но я
not a believer is not for you it's kind of the same
не верующий не по вас это вроде же
public holiday like dna
государственный праздник вроде днк
high on the weekend have to say
высотой на выходной есть сказать
sunday this heart is good just
воскресенье это сердце хорошо просто
rolling someone up to the situation so litter the shaft
катя кого до ситуация так подстилку вал
from the press to Ukraine in a heap about and and
из прессы на к украины ворохом про и и
cut not and dachas and about th not that for what
стричь не и дачи и про th не то ибо чем
giving the enemy actually in cold blood
дачу ворог фактически хладнокровно
other countries
стран же еще
about good russia for 1 but there is no not
про хорошо россии за 1 а тут нет не
passed and two daneth screeching about the planet
прошло и два данетом визг про планете
yavin and cbd wings for russia and all this
явин и cbd крылья для руси и этому всю
blame needy continue tobacco
вину потребного продолжу табачной
Russians and clogs themselves magazines are such a morning
россиян и сами сабо журналов такие утру
Lee Chun Ying's spirit can't just take it and
дух ли чун ин не может просто взять и бы
you steven allah this place had to
ты стивен аллы этого места на пришлось
you are this vinci crap like yourself
вы этой винчи хрень как самого
have to go out and after an hour and
приходуется выходит и пройдя час и
issued by Ukraine we are looking for us sprats in
выдаются украины мы ищем нас кильки в
her on rasputin and think it's dead and
ней на распутин и думаете это погибших и
economical and become and we start
экономично и становятся и мы начинаем
this seems like all kinds of laevsky
этом казаться за лаевский все вида им
there those areas number grind we crumbs
там те области номер измельчу мы трошки
for Russia, let us ourselves image and
за россии пусть мы сами имиджем и
categories us to find what will tell you to enter
категориям нам найти что скажет войти в
city ​​to return Yanukovych from the ruble and
город вернуть януковича из рубль и
dollar will hang if me your misc
доллар повисит если мне ваш разное
it was milked for an hour on the keel of the cyst who
доится было час на киль кисты кто
wants to turn and Yanukovych but still
захочет повернут и януковича но еще
Ukrainians live I don't know there russian is
украинцы живу я не знаю там russian это
cal Ukrainians
кал украинцы
boring and with this from the category of whiners
нудным и с этим из категории нытики
fridge to hold'em who survived it
холодильник до холдеме кто выжил его
thing there already near the chateau be here she is
штука там уж около шато be here she is
you so you quite clinch lot us a
ты так ты совсем клинче лот нам а
gasoline at a time because of when you're friends
бензина за раз из-за when you дружу
Michurin so changed the truth people once
мичурина так менял истины люди разу
nothing to blame and say
ничего вина и скажем
Let a June blackness in on I think
пусть а в июне черноте в на я думаю
swiftness on the shaft archive and right now we
стремительностью на валу архив а щас мы
already to break the damage we understand as
уже переломать им ущерб мы разумеем как
I myself will also talk about Grisha, the Vinnytsia section
сам еще про гришу секция винница буду
roses on the track long shahin track glory
роз по трассе давно шахин трасса слава
Ukraine
украине